<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Republished verge Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is the scheduled republished verge RSS Feed.]]></description><link>https://zmattingly.github.io/rss-republish</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:03:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zmattingly.github.io/rss-republish/verge.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bluetti SwapSolar review: power and chill with swappable batteries]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>Sharing this solar generator’s batteries with a 3-in-1 solar fridge, freezer, and ice-making combo is a good idea that might get better.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="UK8dnL">Solar generators and battery-powered fridges are highly desirable additions to vans, boats, cabins, and sheds, or anywhere power and refrigeration is needed off the grid. Both are meant to be portable by necessity but suffer from the same issue: weight. </p>
<p id="bpxFI6">Bluetti just started shipping its <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bluettipower.com%2Fpages%2Fac180t&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">SwapSolar kit</a> that pairs an AC180T solar generator with its MultiCooler, a 3-in-1 solar-powered fridge, freezer, and ice maker. What makes this kit interesting is that the MultiCooler and AC180T devices can share the same B70 LFP batteries, which can be charged inside either device when plugged into your car’s 12V socket, a standard power outlet, or solar panels. </p>
<p id="src0dI">This modular approach has some other interesting benefits, too:</p>
<ul>
<li id="tLSJjz">Divide these heavy devices into multiple components for easier transport.</li>
<li id="fQL8bL">Worry less about charging batteries or buying bigger ones by getting as many B70 batteries as you need to cover your average roadtrip, workday, or home blackout.</li>
<li id="DN6Lhn">Repair or replace just the battery or the unit it powers should something go wrong or upgrades become available.</li>
</ul>
<p id="MzmJif">Building a modular ecosystem of products around small interchangeable batteries has already seen success by makers of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/3/20/17141972/makita-cm501dz-rugged-coffee-maker-cordless">handheld power tools</a>. Bluetti is expanding the concept to devices needed for extended off-grid living, with more SwapSolar products coming. </p>
<p id="C4Q9Fb">Great, but first we need to see if the devices shipping today can independently justify the total price of the $2,000 SwapSolar kit. </p>
<p id="e6K6SX"><em><strong>Editor’s note: </strong></em><em>When this review was finished, we went back to take one last photo and discovered that the MultiCooler would not turn on for reasons explained below. We are therefore withholding its score until Bluetti can assure us it’s not a widespread defect.</em></p>
<div>
<div id="7P4JvO"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12324084"></div></div>
<div id="7tymy5"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12324085"></div></div>
</div>
<p id="iuLYGm">The SwapSolar B70 battery at the heart of these systems holds 716.8Wh of energy and is built using LFP chemistry. LFP — short for lithium iron phosphate — batteries last longer, are safer, and work in a wider range of operating temperatures than the smaller and lighter NMC-based batteries they’re rapidly replacing. The B70 should hold 80 percent of its original charging capacity, even after 3,000 cycles.</p>
<p id="B5ZqtP">Bluetti will sell you as many B70 batteries as you’d like, but right now, they only work with the AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler. The AC180T can be powered by one or two batteries, while the MultiCooler fits only one.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Irce7ULMeUZJ1BlFzRCIgpYTY6w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25466129/Hover_20240426_1714137151896.0_ezgif.com_optimize_ezgif.com_optimize.gif">
      <figcaption><em>The AC180T solar generator fitted with two hot-swappable B70 batteries will continue charging my laptop uninterrupted after one battery is removed to power the MultiCooler.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<h2 id="HVlSBk">MultiCooler </h2>
<p id="zjtMLD">The 3-in-1 MultiCooler (model F045D) refrigerator, freezer, and ice maker is very similar to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23987611/ecoflow-glacier-review-ice-maker-refrigerator-freezer-vanlife-boatlife-specs-price">EcoFlow Glacier I reviewed</a> last year. However, the MultiCooler lacks EcoFlow’s dual-zone feature that lets you divide the main compartment into both a freezer and fridge that can run <em>simultaneously</em>. That could be a deal-breaker for some. On the other hand, Bluetti’s MultiCooler runs longer on battery and is usually a little quieter.</p>
<p id="TGqHkR">Noise is a critical factor for any device that runs all night within earshot of your bed in an RV, cabin, or boat. Bluetti’s MultiCooler is thankfully nearly silent until the compressor kicks in. Then it gets about as loud as a home theater projector, or about 35dB in my testing, as it cools the unit down. Cooling is relatively slow, however. Even with the refrigeration mode set to Max in the Bluetti app, it took 23 minutes to go from room temperature to 6 degrees Celsius / 43 degrees Fahrenheit and then another 17 minutes to reach -10C / 14F. That’s slower, but quieter, than the EcoFlow Glacier.</p>
<div id="5teQHe"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12325428"></div></div>
<p id="eMaG7Q">Bluetti consistently reported a lower temperature than my own trusty thermometer during testing. For example, my thermometer placed inside the unit read -8C / 17.6F when the app and MultiCooler display read -10C / 14F, and when the MultiCooler said it was 3C / 37.4F, the thermometer read 5C / 41F. At least it was consistently inconsistent, which is something I can work around.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vBKxMxCAO6gKeAQ5ErSfAnsQ0HI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25431529/IMG_4066.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Smart plug visualization showing the MultiCooler operating as a refrigerator before 11AM and freezer after. Each power spike corresponds to the compressor coming on to cool the device. It used 308Wh from the wall jack on this particular day.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="jxZxQX">The unit goes almost completely silent once it hits your defined temperature set in the app or on the physical display, interrupted by a few bubbles and scratches now and again that likely won’t be too annoying for most people. The compressor runs for about 10 minutes at around 33dB, followed by 20- to 40-minute gaps of near silence in my testing. It turns on with what sounds like five distinct clicks of a mechanical button and turns off with a slight rattle that’s noticeable when empty (the lightweight food baskets inside the fridge shake).</p>
<p id="TaGfC1">Ice making is a much noisier affair, as you’d expect, and occurs in its own dedicated compartment — not in the freezer. The first batch of ice takes about 23 minutes as the MultiCooler produces a loud 48dB from a distance of one meter. The noise is constant and only stops about one minute before the ice drops into the bucket. Each batch thereafter is just as loud but only takes about 12 minutes. You can select between small or large ice, which yields a sheet of two dozen small (or less small) hollow cubes. It can produce ice continuously until the one-liter water reservoir is empty — that’s about 100 cubes. In my testing, the ice was about half melted after being left in the closed bucket for six hours.</p>
<p id="L4uhZV">One quirk of making ice is that Bluetti stops cooling the main compartment to do it. That should be fine in all but the hottest environments, so long as the lid is left closed. To test the quality of the insulation, I turned off the MultiCooler that had been operating for a day at -10C / 14F while half full of frozen food. According to the app, it measured -8C / 17.6F after one hour, -6C / 21.2 F after two hours, and -5C / 23F after three hours. It was still at 1C / 34F some 14 hours later.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><div id="02mIGp"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12321371"></div></div></div>
<p id="COVGRq">Battery life is very good. In Max refrigeration mode, I was able to bring the temperature down to -10C / 14F, make four batches of ice, and then maintain that temperature for 36 hours before a recharge was needed. In Eco mode, I started the timer when the temperature was already -10C / 14F, made two batches of ice, and maintained the temperature for 40 hours before the battery died. In both cases, the battery quit inelegantly with an E1 error (low battery voltage protection) at about 5 percent charge left. Bluetti tells me “this is normal” which is... come on.</p>
<p id="WF5D6r">Bluetti provides adapters to power the MultiCooler by three other methods: a 12V / 24V DC connection to a car socket; a standard AC wall jack; or up to 200W of direct connected solar panels, but only if there’s a battery inside. Bluetti didn’t provide any charging data like watts, voltage, and current when I connected a 200W solar panel to the MultiCooler — it just shows it charging on the display and in the app. The unit can make ice no matter how the unit is powered, unlike the EcoFlow Glacier.</p>
<p id="LuH6wU">The MultiCooler includes a handle and wheels as standard, which make it relatively easy to transport over flat ground when fully loaded. It’s still heavy even without the B70 battery installed, and the wheels are rather small, resulting in limited ground clearance — that means occasionally having to drag the MultiCooler over rougher terrains.</p>
<p id="uUzdW2">Unfortunately, as I was wrapping up this review, I found that the MultiCooler would not turn on after sitting idle for about a week. It is now back with Bluetti, and a preliminary report suggests that my issue was caused by a heatsink detaching from a MOS tube — a critical voltage control element on the MultiCooler’s circuitry — possibly as a result of rough handling during shipment. Bluetti will now determine if this is a one-off situation or a general defect that requires changes in the manufacturing and assembly process. </p>
<p id="1GF5dg">We will update this review and add a MultiCooler score when we get the final analysis from Bluetti.</p>
<p id="9VIyxc">I should also note that while 3-in-1 fridge, freezer, and ice-making combos are impressive in all they can do, they are also expensive compared to simple 12V portable car fridges that cost less than half as much. But those won’t make ice from the power of the Saharan sun, so what’s even the point?</p>
<h2 id="ak8Iv9">AC180T </h2>
<p id="niGiVE">The AC180T solar generator is a nicely designed power station with a built-in MPPT charge controller to connect solar panels. Nearly all the outputs and display can be conveniently found on the front, with the AC input on the side. A lid on the top hides the two B70 slots, which are keyed to ensure the batteries are inserted correctly, for a total capacity of 1.43kWh.</p>
<p id="TEp5zg">For context, 1.43kWh is enough to keep a 6000BTU window air conditioner (400W) running for about six hours, boil about 35 liters of water from a 1000W electric kettle, or keep a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23181342/starlink-rv-review-trees-rain-speed-latency">Starlink internet from space system</a> running for about a day and a half.</p>
<p id="BseOvA">Bluetti’s modular approach really helps to divvy up the weight of the AC180T. Each 5.3 × 6.3 × 13.8in / 134 × 160 × 350mm battery weighs 18.7lbs / 8.5kg, which brings the total weight of the AC180T up to 58.4lbs / 26.5kg when both are inserted — that’s a lot for most people to carry.</p>
<div id="FFg1CF"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12325433"></div></div>
<p id="DGCmUv">When plugged into an AC wall jack and in the fastest “Turbo” mode, charging two batteries from zero to 100 percent took 77 minutes and produced about 44dB of noise (from one meter away) while drawing 1.4kW from the grid. Charging in Standard mode still produced 44dB but pulled only 920W, while Silent mode dropped things down to 37dB and 735W. Charging a single battery in Turbo mode took 66 minutes and pulled a steady 860W. In all cases, charging began to slow down at around 95 percent full, as you’d expect.</p>
<p id="Zw6ov4">I also tested Bluetti’s claim that the AC180T can produce up to 1200W of continuous AC output with one battery inserted or up to 1800W with two hot-swappable batteries.</p>
<p id="iEf7xo">With one battery installed, I was able to run a microwave at around 1250W for three minutes without issue, but a 2100W hair dryer resulted in an inverter overload, causing it to shut down for safety. I then added the second battery and plugged in the same hair dryer, which ran fine at a steady 1874W, until I plugged in a 1200W toaster for a total load of 3074W, which quickly shut down the inverter with another overload. No smells, no funny noises, no mess, as you’d hope. So, both tests passed.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><div id="rFQhJA"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12321372"></div></div></div>
<p id="YyhZzj">To test the hot-swappable claim, I started the 1250W microwave with two batteries inserted. It continued to run as I removed and reinserted one of the batteries. I then unplugged the microwave and plugged in the hair dryer, drawing 900W, which continued to blow as I removed and reinserted a battery. I then bumped the heat to max (drawing over 1850W) with two batteries installed, pulled one, and the hair dryer shut off within seconds. Good.</p>
<p id="pb4yqo">As with all power stations, the AC inverter will drain the battery when left on. With no load attached and the AC output turned on, my two AC180T batteries (1.43kWh) dropped 30 percent in 24 hours. That works out to about 17.92Wh lost per hour, or a steady 18W just to power the inverter, which is fairly efficient. Still, you should enable Bluetti’s AC Eco mode (on by default) to automatically turn off the AC inverter after a user-defined time of low or no load. Otherwise, those fully charged batteries will die in just over three days.</p>
<p id="4WEInu">For what it’s worth, I was able to plug the MultiCooler directly into the 12V / 10A DC car jack on the AC180T with the included cable, which obviates the need to swap batteries if you can keep the units close together. You can also power the fridge off the AC180T’s AC port, of course, but DC is more efficient (no wasteful inverter). </p>
<p id="mdDuT3">The Bluetti app is fine, but it’s cluttered with promotions and only works with the MultiCooler and AC180T over Bluetooth, not Wi-Fi like EcoFlow’s products. That means you’ll have to be nearby to check on your battery status or to adjust temperatures.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K6WKfc4WOcwkto39qvpDPfzmYaw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25434067/Hover_20240425_1714135816951.0.jpeg">
      <figcaption><em>Me writing this review from a remote workplace flanked by a Bluetti AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler to keep my Negroni on ice.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="ADSDKf">Conclusion</h2>
<p id="GMpSwd">On their own, the SwapSolar AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler 3-in-1 fridge are each very competitive products — assuming, of course, that the defect on my MultiCooler review unit was an isolated issue. If so, then Bluetti’s SwapSolar kit is a winning combination.</p>
<p id="3AM8J4">Regardless, I hope to see Bluetti’s modular ecosystem approach adopted by competitors like EcoFlow, Jackery, and others. A company called <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.runhoodpower.com%2Fproducts%2Frallye-1200-pro-1296wh-1200w-portable-power-station-with-100w-solar-panel%3Fvariant%3D47815111639354&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Runhood</a> has already been selling less powerful <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.runhoodpower.com%2Fproducts%2Frallye-1200-pro-1296wh-1200w-portable-power-station-with-100w-solar-panel&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">solar generators with modular batteries</a> and accessories for over a year.</p>
<p id="3ewdOG">What SwapSolar is missing, however, is a small portable charging accessory to independently charge each B70 battery. Bluetti’s Evelyn Zou tells me that a “base” is in development to do exactly that. Then you only need to bring the base and battery into a shop, cafe, or gym to get things charged, instead of conspicuously dragging in the entire fridge or solar generator. The base will also convert the B70 battery into a standalone power source for your USB gadgets. Zou says that Bluetti is looking to expand the SwapSolar ecosystem in the future and is “actively working on new products.” But those are just promises for now, with no dates or prices. </p>
<p id="4arhCZ">Ideally, owners of the AC180T and MultiCooler and any other SwapSolar device could even upgrade to compatible batteries with improved chemistry over time. Or maybe it opens up a market to cheaper third-party alternatives. We’ll see!</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="4FBWpQ"><q>For the MultiCooler, my advice is to wait or look elsewhere until Bluetti explains itself</q></aside></div>
<p id="8RaKOZ">Bluetti is selling the <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bluettipower.com%2Fproducts%2Fac180t&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AC180T directly for $1,099</a>. But the MultiCooler is still in that weird <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%23%2F&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Indiegogo “indemand” phase</a> — which means you’ll have to wait until August, according to Bluetti, if you prefer to buy directly from the company and avoid all the Indiegogo “perk” nonsense. The AC180T is covered by a five-year warranty, which drops to two years for the MultiCooler.</p>
<p id="77CRjS">For the MultiCooler, my advice is to wait or look elsewhere until Bluetti explains itself. </p>
<p id="0pa0N7">The SwapSolar MultiCooler and AC180T combo kit is currently priced at <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$1,999</a> on Indiegogo. That sounds about right given that a comparable system from EcoFlow that combines the Glacier 3-in-1 fridge with a less powerful River 2 Pro solar generator currently sells for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fglacier-portable-refrigerator-river-2-pro-portable-power-station-1%3Fvariant%3D40540240478281&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$1,499</a> or <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fglacier-portable-refrigerator-delta-2-max-portable-power-station%3Fvariant%3D40543489818697&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$2,799 when paired with a more powerful Delta 2 Max</a>. The AC180T lists for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$999</a> while the MultiCooler can be purchased separately for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$799</a> (without a B70 battery).</p>
<p id="7k3bSw"><em>Photography by Thomas Ricker / The Verge</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24145138/multicooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24145138/multicooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 06:18:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bluetti SwapSolar review: power and chill with swappable batteries]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>Sharing this solar generator’s batteries with a 3-in-1 solar fridge, freezer, and ice-making combo is a good idea that might get better.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="UK8dnL">Solar generators and battery-powered fridges are highly desirable additions to vans, boats, cabins, and sheds, or anywhere power and refrigeration is needed off the grid. Both are meant to be portable by necessity but suffer from the same issue: weight. </p>
<p id="bpxFI6">Bluetti just started shipping its <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bluettipower.com%2Fpages%2Fac180t&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">SwapSolar kit</a> that pairs an AC180T solar generator with its MultiCooler, a 3-in-1 solar-powered fridge, freezer, and ice maker. What makes this kit interesting is that the MultiCooler and AC180T devices can share the same B70 LFP batteries, which can be charged inside either device when plugged into your car’s 12V socket, a standard power outlet, or solar panels. </p>
<p id="src0dI">This modular approach has some other interesting benefits, too:</p>
<ul>
<li id="tLSJjz">Divide these heavy devices into multiple components for easier transport.</li>
<li id="fQL8bL">Worry less about charging batteries or buying bigger ones by getting as many B70 batteries as you need to cover your average roadtrip, workday, or home blackout.</li>
<li id="DN6Lhn">Repair or replace just the battery or the unit it powers should something go wrong or upgrades become available.</li>
</ul>
<p id="MzmJif">Building a modular ecosystem of products around small interchangeable batteries has already seen success by makers of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/3/20/17141972/makita-cm501dz-rugged-coffee-maker-cordless">handheld power tools</a>. Bluetti is expanding the concept to devices needed for extended off-grid living, with more SwapSolar products coming. </p>
<p id="C4Q9Fb">Great, but first we need to see if the devices shipping today can independently justify the total price of the $2,000 SwapSolar kit. </p>
<p id="e6K6SX"><em><strong>Editor’s note: </strong></em><em>When this review was finished, we went back to take one last photo and discovered that the MultiCooler would not turn on for reasons explained below. We are therefore withholding its score until Bluetti can assure us it’s not a widespread defect.</em></p>
<div>
<div id="7P4JvO"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12324084"></div></div>
<div id="7tymy5"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12324085"></div></div>
</div>
<p id="iuLYGm">The SwapSolar B70 battery at the heart of these systems holds 716.8Wh of energy and is built using LFP chemistry. LFP — short for lithium iron phosphate — batteries last longer, are safer, and work in a wider range of operating temperatures than the smaller and lighter NMC-based batteries they’re rapidly replacing. The B70 should hold 80 percent of its original charging capacity, even after 3,000 cycles.</p>
<p id="B5ZqtP">Bluetti will sell you as many B70 batteries as you’d like, but right now, they only work with the AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler. The AC180T can be powered by one or two batteries, while the MultiCooler fits only one.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Irce7ULMeUZJ1BlFzRCIgpYTY6w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25466129/Hover_20240426_1714137151896.0_ezgif.com_optimize_ezgif.com_optimize.gif">
      <figcaption><em>The AC180T solar generator fitted with two hot-swappable B70 batteries will continue charging my laptop uninterrupted after one battery is removed to power the MultiCooler.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<h2 id="HVlSBk">MultiCooler </h2>
<p id="zjtMLD">The 3-in-1 MultiCooler (model F045D) refrigerator, freezer, and ice maker is very similar to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23987611/ecoflow-glacier-review-ice-maker-refrigerator-freezer-vanlife-boatlife-specs-price">EcoFlow Glacier I reviewed</a> last year. However, the MultiCooler lacks EcoFlow’s dual-zone feature that lets you divide the main compartment into both a freezer and fridge that can run <em>simultaneously</em>. That could be a deal-breaker for some. On the other hand, Bluetti’s MultiCooler runs longer on battery and is usually a little quieter.</p>
<p id="TGqHkR">Noise is a critical factor for any device that runs all night within earshot of your bed in an RV, cabin, or boat. Bluetti’s MultiCooler is thankfully nearly silent until the compressor kicks in. Then it gets about as loud as a home theater projector, or about 35dB in my testing, as it cools the unit down. Cooling is relatively slow, however. Even with the refrigeration mode set to Max in the Bluetti app, it took 23 minutes to go from room temperature to 6 degrees Celsius / 43 degrees Fahrenheit and then another 17 minutes to reach -10C / 14F. That’s slower, but quieter, than the EcoFlow Glacier.</p>
<div id="5teQHe"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12325428"></div></div>
<p id="eMaG7Q">Bluetti consistently reported a lower temperature than my own trusty thermometer during testing. For example, my thermometer placed inside the unit read -8C / 17.6F when the app and MultiCooler display read -10C / 14F, and when the MultiCooler said it was 3C / 37.4F, the thermometer read 5C / 41F. At least it was consistently inconsistent, which is something I can work around.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vBKxMxCAO6gKeAQ5ErSfAnsQ0HI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25431529/IMG_4066.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Smart plug visualization showing the MultiCooler operating as a refrigerator before 11AM and freezer after. Each power spike corresponds to the compressor coming on to cool the device. It used 308Wh from the wall jack on this particular day.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="jxZxQX">The unit goes almost completely silent once it hits your defined temperature set in the app or on the physical display, interrupted by a few bubbles and scratches now and again that likely won’t be too annoying for most people. The compressor runs for about 10 minutes at around 33dB, followed by 20- to 40-minute gaps of near silence in my testing. It turns on with what sounds like five distinct clicks of a mechanical button and turns off with a slight rattle that’s noticeable when empty (the lightweight food baskets inside the fridge shake).</p>
<p id="TaGfC1">Ice making is a much noisier affair, as you’d expect, and occurs in its own dedicated compartment — not in the freezer. The first batch of ice takes about 23 minutes as the MultiCooler produces a loud 48dB from a distance of one meter. The noise is constant and only stops about one minute before the ice drops into the bucket. Each batch thereafter is just as loud but only takes about 12 minutes. You can select between small or large ice, which yields a sheet of two dozen small (or less small) hollow cubes. It can produce ice continuously until the one-liter water reservoir is empty — that’s about 100 cubes. In my testing, the ice was about half melted after being left in the closed bucket for six hours.</p>
<p id="L4uhZV">One quirk of making ice is that Bluetti stops cooling the main compartment to do it. That should be fine in all but the hottest environments, so long as the lid is left closed. To test the quality of the insulation, I turned off the MultiCooler that had been operating for a day at -10C / 14F while half full of frozen food. According to the app, it measured -8C / 17.6F after one hour, -6C / 21.2 F after two hours, and -5C / 23F after three hours. It was still at 1C / 34F some 14 hours later.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><div id="02mIGp"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12321371"></div></div></div>
<p id="COVGRq">Battery life is very good. In Max refrigeration mode, I was able to bring the temperature down to -10C / 14F, make four batches of ice, and then maintain that temperature for 36 hours before a recharge was needed. In Eco mode, I started the timer when the temperature was already -10C / 14F, made two batches of ice, and maintained the temperature for 40 hours before the battery died. In both cases, the battery quit inelegantly with an E1 error (low battery voltage protection) at about 5 percent charge left. Bluetti tells me “this is normal” which is... come on.</p>
<p id="WF5D6r">Bluetti provides adapters to power the MultiCooler by three other methods: a 12V / 24V DC connection to a car socket; a standard AC wall jack; or up to 200W of direct connected solar panels, but only if there’s a battery inside. Bluetti didn’t provide any charging data like watts, voltage, and current when I connected a 200W solar panel to the MultiCooler — it just shows it charging on the display and in the app. The unit can make ice no matter how the unit is powered, unlike the EcoFlow Glacier.</p>
<p id="LuH6wU">The MultiCooler includes a handle and wheels as standard, which make it relatively easy to transport over flat ground when fully loaded. It’s still heavy even without the B70 battery installed, and the wheels are rather small, resulting in limited ground clearance — that means occasionally having to drag the MultiCooler over rougher terrains.</p>
<p id="uUzdW2">Unfortunately, as I was wrapping up this review, I found that the MultiCooler would not turn on after sitting idle for about a week. It is now back with Bluetti, and a preliminary report suggests that my issue was caused by a heatsink detaching from a MOS tube — a critical voltage control element on the MultiCooler’s circuitry — possibly as a result of rough handling during shipment. Bluetti will now determine if this is a one-off situation or a general defect that requires changes in the manufacturing and assembly process. </p>
<p id="1GF5dg">We will update this review and add a MultiCooler score when we get the final analysis from Bluetti.</p>
<p id="9VIyxc">I should also note that while 3-in-1 fridge, freezer, and ice-making combos are impressive in all they can do, they are also expensive compared to simple 12V portable car fridges that cost less than half as much. But those won’t make ice from the power of the Saharan sun, so what’s even the point?</p>
<h2 id="ak8Iv9">AC180T </h2>
<p id="niGiVE">The AC180T solar generator is a nicely designed power station with a built-in MPPT charge controller to connect solar panels. Nearly all the outputs and display can be conveniently found on the front, with the AC input on the side. A lid on the top hides the two B70 slots, which are keyed to ensure the batteries are inserted correctly, for a total capacity of 1.43kWh.</p>
<p id="TEp5zg">For context, 1.43kWh is enough to keep a 6000BTU window air conditioner (400W) running for about six hours, boil about 35 liters of water from a 1000W electric kettle, or keep a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23181342/starlink-rv-review-trees-rain-speed-latency">Starlink internet from space system</a> running for about a day and a half.</p>
<p id="BseOvA">Bluetti’s modular approach really helps to divvy up the weight of the AC180T. Each 5.3 × 6.3 × 13.8in / 134 × 160 × 350mm battery weighs 18.7lbs / 8.5kg, which brings the total weight of the AC180T up to 58.4lbs / 26.5kg when both are inserted — that’s a lot for most people to carry.</p>
<div id="FFg1CF"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12325433"></div></div>
<p id="DGCmUv">When plugged into an AC wall jack and in the fastest “Turbo” mode, charging two batteries from zero to 100 percent took 77 minutes and produced about 44dB of noise (from one meter away) while drawing 1.4kW from the grid. Charging in Standard mode still produced 44dB but pulled only 920W, while Silent mode dropped things down to 37dB and 735W. Charging a single battery in Turbo mode took 66 minutes and pulled a steady 860W. In all cases, charging began to slow down at around 95 percent full, as you’d expect.</p>
<p id="Zw6ov4">I also tested Bluetti’s claim that the AC180T can produce up to 1200W of continuous AC output with one battery inserted or up to 1800W with two hot-swappable batteries.</p>
<p id="iEf7xo">With one battery installed, I was able to run a microwave at around 1250W for three minutes without issue, but a 2100W hair dryer resulted in an inverter overload, causing it to shut down for safety. I then added the second battery and plugged in the same hair dryer, which ran fine at a steady 1874W, until I plugged in a 1200W toaster for a total load of 3074W, which quickly shut down the inverter with another overload. No smells, no funny noises, no mess, as you’d hope. So, both tests passed.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><div id="rFQhJA"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12321372"></div></div></div>
<p id="YyhZzj">To test the hot-swappable claim, I started the 1250W microwave with two batteries inserted. It continued to run as I removed and reinserted one of the batteries. I then unplugged the microwave and plugged in the hair dryer, drawing 900W, which continued to blow as I removed and reinserted a battery. I then bumped the heat to max (drawing over 1850W) with two batteries installed, pulled one, and the hair dryer shut off within seconds. Good.</p>
<p id="pb4yqo">As with all power stations, the AC inverter will drain the battery when left on. With no load attached and the AC output turned on, my two AC180T batteries (1.43kWh) dropped 30 percent in 24 hours. That works out to about 17.92Wh lost per hour, or a steady 18W just to power the inverter, which is fairly efficient. Still, you should enable Bluetti’s AC Eco mode (on by default) to automatically turn off the AC inverter after a user-defined time of low or no load. Otherwise, those fully charged batteries will die in just over three days.</p>
<p id="4WEInu">For what it’s worth, I was able to plug the MultiCooler directly into the 12V / 10A DC car jack on the AC180T with the included cable, which obviates the need to swap batteries if you can keep the units close together. You can also power the fridge off the AC180T’s AC port, of course, but DC is more efficient (no wasteful inverter). </p>
<p id="mdDuT3">The Bluetti app is fine, but it’s cluttered with promotions and only works with the MultiCooler and AC180T over Bluetooth, not Wi-Fi like EcoFlow’s products. That means you’ll have to be nearby to check on your battery status or to adjust temperatures.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K6WKfc4WOcwkto39qvpDPfzmYaw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25434067/Hover_20240425_1714135816951.0.jpeg">
      <figcaption><em>Me writing this review from a remote workplace flanked by a Bluetti AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler to keep my Negroni on ice.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="ADSDKf">Conclusion</h2>
<p id="GMpSwd">On their own, the SwapSolar AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler 3-in-1 fridge are each very competitive products — assuming, of course, that the defect on my MultiCooler review unit was an isolated issue. If so, then Bluetti’s SwapSolar kit is a winning combination.</p>
<p id="3AM8J4">Regardless, I hope to see Bluetti’s modular ecosystem approach adopted by competitors like EcoFlow, Jackery, and others. A company called <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.runhoodpower.com%2Fproducts%2Frallye-1200-pro-1296wh-1200w-portable-power-station-with-100w-solar-panel%3Fvariant%3D47815111639354&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Runhood</a> has already been selling less powerful <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.runhoodpower.com%2Fproducts%2Frallye-1200-pro-1296wh-1200w-portable-power-station-with-100w-solar-panel&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">solar generators with modular batteries</a> and accessories for over a year.</p>
<p id="3ewdOG">What SwapSolar is missing, however, is a small portable charging accessory to independently charge each B70 battery. Bluetti’s Evelyn Zou tells me that a “base” is in development to do exactly that. Then you only need to bring the base and battery into a shop, cafe, or gym to get things charged, instead of conspicuously dragging in the entire fridge or solar generator. The base will also convert the B70 battery into a standalone power source for your USB gadgets. Zou says that Bluetti is looking to expand the SwapSolar ecosystem in the future and is “actively working on new products.” But those are just promises for now, with no dates or prices. </p>
<p id="4arhCZ">Ideally, owners of the AC180T and MultiCooler and any other SwapSolar device could even upgrade to compatible batteries with improved chemistry over time. Or maybe it opens up a market to cheaper third-party alternatives. We’ll see!</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="4FBWpQ"><q>For the MultiCooler, my advice is to wait or look elsewhere until Bluetti explains itself</q></aside></div>
<p id="8RaKOZ">Bluetti is selling the <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bluettipower.com%2Fproducts%2Fac180t&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AC180T directly for $1,099</a>. But the MultiCooler is still in that weird <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%23%2F&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Indiegogo “indemand” phase</a> — which means you’ll have to wait until August, according to Bluetti, if you prefer to buy directly from the company and avoid all the Indiegogo “perk” nonsense. The AC180T is covered by a five-year warranty, which drops to two years for the MultiCooler.</p>
<p id="77CRjS">For the MultiCooler, my advice is to wait or look elsewhere until Bluetti explains itself. </p>
<p id="0pa0N7">The SwapSolar MultiCooler and AC180T combo kit is currently priced at <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$1,999</a> on Indiegogo. That sounds about right given that a comparable system from EcoFlow that combines the Glacier 3-in-1 fridge with a less powerful River 2 Pro solar generator currently sells for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fglacier-portable-refrigerator-river-2-pro-portable-power-station-1%3Fvariant%3D40540240478281&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$1,499</a> or <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fglacier-portable-refrigerator-delta-2-max-portable-power-station%3Fvariant%3D40543489818697&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$2,799 when paired with a more powerful Delta 2 Max</a>. The AC180T lists for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$999</a> while the MultiCooler can be purchased separately for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$799</a> (without a B70 battery).</p>
<p id="7k3bSw"><em>Photography by Thomas Ricker / The Verge</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24145138/multicooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24145138/multicooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 06:18:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[This app put my Apple Home smart devices into an interactive map]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GiKv2XI4zBmjZdY6_yBiplWKTAA=/32x0:4106x2716/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73375248/multiple_screens_high_resolution_overview_controller_7_0.0.png" />
        <figcaption><em>Using Apple’s RoomPlan Controller for HomeKit has added a map view for Apple Home to its app.</em> | Image: Controller for HomeKit</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="m_423877033755796297dataBlockId-27"><a href="https://app.us13.list-manage.com/track/click?u=a57d0dc65ce56ec591cd2550d&amp;id=ef3e3d9955&amp;e=33775aafb2">Controller for HomeKit</a>, a third-party app for controlling your Apple Home smart home, has a new <a href="https://homedevices.app/create-an-apple-home-floor-plan-with-a-lidar-sensor/">Floor Plan feature</a> that adds a map interface for interacting with connected devices like lights, locks, shades, sensors and more. I got some time with the new feature ahead of its launch this week and it’s a compelling way to control your smart home. A 3D scan of your house becomes an interactive map filled with all your connected devices providing an intuitive way to control them: Just tap the lamp next to the sofa on the map and that light will turn on.  </p>
<p id="taPRRb">For those unfamiliar, Controller for HomeKit is a well-regarded app that can manage and control any Apple Home and HomeKit compatible devices, scenes, automations, and so on. It uses <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/homekit/">the HomeKit framework</a> meaning it works exactly like the Apple Home app, but it offers <a href="https://controllerforhomekit.com/">more complex automations and advanced notifications</a> than the Home app. This makes it a good option for those who like Apple Home but find Apple’s own app too limited. </p>
<p id="ZG8CBe"><a href="https://homedevices.app/create-an-apple-home-floor-plan-with-a-lidar-sensor/">Floor Plan</a> arrives with version 7.0 of Controller for HomeKit (iOS only), which also brings a complete redesign to the app, putting the new control feature front and center. This map-style interface provides an easier way for everyone in your house to control your smart home without having to memorize phrases like, “Siri, turn off left sofa lamp” or scrolling through a list of awkward names in an app. </p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="y2Yyf7"><q>The Floor Plan feature is part of a paid subscription and requires a LIDAR-enabled iPhone or iPad.</q></aside></div>
<p id="KC4Ics">Because of this ease of use, map view is becoming a popular control method for the home; both <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/14/23960355/amazon-alexa-map-view-launch-public-preview">Amazon Alexa</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/11/24035395/samsungs-map-view-looks-sweet-on-that-big-smart-display-i-mean-television">Samsung SmartThings</a> added a similar interface to their smart home control apps last year. Controlling gadgets on a map feels more intuitive than the current clunky state of voice control and is more visual than most of today’s app-based controls.</p>
<p id="YGeDJG">I’ve been playing with the new Floor Plan feature for about a day, and I like how it gives me a quick way to control multiple devices from one screen. I can tap the lamp in my living room, view a livestream from the camera in my kitchen, lock the front door, and see the temperature from the Hue Motion sensor in my dining room all in one place. Without the Floor Plan, that would require multiple taps and swipes, unless I had those devices set as favorites or tiles in my Control Panel on my iPhone. </p>
<p id="q07Sws">I’ve also tried <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/14/23960355/amazon-alexa-map-view-launch-public-preview">Amazon’s Map View feature </a>and in practice it’s very similar. The biggest difference I’ve noticed so far is that I couldn’t add my HomePods to the Floor Plan, whereas I could add Amazon’s Echo speakers to the Alexa map view and control volume and playback directly from there. </p>
<div id="n7ip6A"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12343695"></div></div>
<p id="odJMoF">Setting up Floor Plan was simple. The scanning feature is powered by <a href="https://developer.apple.com/augmented-reality/roomplan/">Apple’s RoomPlan</a>, a Swift API that uses the camera and LIDAR scanner on certain iPhone and iPad models to create a 3D floor plan (this is the same for the Amazon Alexa version). </p>
<p id="s7SADk">Using my iPhone 15 Pro, I walked through my house, slowly guiding my camera around each room, watching as the app filled in digital walls and furniture with white lines. The developers behind Controller for HomeKit say all data processing is done locally on the iPhone and that the photos used to generate the floor plan are not being sent to the cloud.</p>
<p id="ZHC56t">It took 15 to 30 seconds to map each room and about five minutes to scan my entire split level downstairs area. The app then stitched the rooms together into a floor plan — I did two floor plans in total, you can do multiple. The floor plans include furniture, windows, doors, and dimensions, which made it easy to see where to add the icons for each device I wanted to place on the map.   </p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="7z2K4A"><div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How the smart home is finally getting out of your phone and into your home","url":"https://www.theverge.com/24043060/smart-home-interface-map-view-samsung-lg-amazon-ces-2024"},{"title":"Apple’s new Home app in iOS 16 is better but still half-baked","url":"https://www.theverge.com/23279283/apple-homekit-home-app-ios16-preview"}]}'></div></aside></div>
<p id="MoscJ5">I had given the app permission to access my HomeKit data, so it knew which devices I had. Once the floor plan was complete, I could select my accessories from a list — lights, locks, thermostats, cameras, sensors, and so on — and add them to the map reflecting where they are in the real world. I could also add HomeKit scenes to each room to control multiple devices with one tap. </p>
<p id="NlH8vR">There’s a free version as well as a paid Pro version of Controller for HomeKit, the latter adds a backup and restore function <a href="https://controllerforhomekit.com/features">among other benefits</a>. It costs $29.99 for one year, or $99.99 for a lifetime license. The Floor Plan feature requires the paid version, but you can try it out for free as part of a 7 day trial. </p>
<p id="4uUOFj">You also need a LIDAR-enabled iPhone or iPad (iPhone 12 Pro, iPad Pro 11 third-gen or newer, or iPad Pro 12.9 fifth-gen or newer) to create the Floor Plan. If you don’t own one but know someone who does, the developers have created an <a href="https://app.us13.list-manage.com/track/click?u=a57d0dc65ce56ec591cd2550d&amp;id=f6efd60cc4&amp;e=33775aafb2">AppClip</a> that lets you create the Floor Plan on a friend’s device and import it to your device.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/phz05ptt6Q8AplvA69jUYLUYtnc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25468523/Screenshot_2024_05_28_at_11.02.46_PM.jpeg">
      <figcaption><em>The Controller for HomeKit iPad app supports the new Floor Plan feature and is a better screen size for interacting with the map than an iPhone.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="bOjYbz">I’m a big proponent of developing <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24043060/smart-home-interface-map-view-samsung-lg-amazon-ces-2024">new and more intuitive ways to control our smart home devices</a>; it’s too easy for them to become the responsibility of the one person in the house who knows how everything works and has all the control apps on their phone. </p>
<p id="gDdT9g">Of course, the natural place for this type of map interface is on a communal device with a large screen, like an iPad or tablet mounted on a wall or a TV. Controller for HomeKit has an iPad app that works with Floor Plan, Samsung’s SmartThings map view is available on its tablets and TVs; and Amazon has said it will bring its map view to its wall-mountable <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/20/23880766/amazon-alexa-echo-hub-smart-displays-price-matter">Echo Hub smart home controller</a> this year. </p>
<p id="0wJG7z">While a map view is a seriously fun tool for smart home nerds like me — it’s like playing with a digital doll house! — the more accessible a feature like Floor Plan is to everyone in the house the more useful I think it will be. I would love to see Apple add a floor plan / map view to the Home app and bring it to Apple TV. Point and click with your remote to turn the lights off? That’s smart.</p>
<p id="HnVBVp"><em>Screenshots by Jennifer Pattison Tuohy / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="MMEqtw"><em><strong>Correction, May 29th: </strong></em><em>An earlier version of this article misstated the pricing of the Pro version of Controller for HomeKit. It is $29.99 per year or $99.99 for a lifetime license, not $14.49 / $29.99. The Floor Plan feature requires the Pro plan.</em></p>
<p id="u59dqD"></p>
<p id="Nj9oZ1"></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/29/24166341/apple-home-floor-plan-controller-for-homekit-app-launch-hands-on</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/29/24166341/apple-home-floor-plan-controller-for-homekit-app-launch-hands-on</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[There’s no easy 3D printer, but Bambu has won me over]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>Bambu P1P vs. Creality K1C: an ‘easy’ 3D printer showdown.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap" id="l1JN6v">If you asked me to recommend an “easy” consumer 3D printer, I’d warn you first: despite countless innovations, you still can’t quite hit a button to reliably photocopy a 3D model. Buying a 3D printer is buying an entire hobby, one where — if you’re a lazy bum like me — many attempts will turn into worthless gobs of plastic.</p>
<p id="kTziu8">But if you persisted, I’d tell you my one clear choice for lazy bums: the Bambu P1P.</p>
<p id="YHivmb">What, a printer from the company that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/4/24061794/bambu-lab-a1-3d-printer-recall-heatbed-cable-damage">recalled its newest model</a> and whose earlier ones <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/16/23064592/bambu-print-asleep-cloud-outage">once went rogue</a>? Yep — because not only did Bambu handle those incidents with rapid apologies, investigations, transparency, and even refunds, the <a href="https://us.store.bambulab.com/products/p1p">$599 Bambu P1P</a> is also absolutely the easiest, most reliable 3D printer I’ve used. </p>
<p id="WIbs3G">It makes my stalwart old Ender 3 Pro look like a hunk of junk. It makes its closest competition, the <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.creality.com%2Fproducts%2Fk1c-3d-printer&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F23924708%2Fcreality-k1c-bambu-p1p-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$559 Creality K1C</a>, feel like an inferior clone. I’ve spent months testing them side by side, and I’d personally pick the Bambu every time.</p>
<p id="g2qFsL">Don’t get me wrong: the K1C is the better choice for some tinkerers since its full enclosure, bed, and extra fan let you print higher temperature plastics like ABS as well as ones reinforced with glass or carbon fibers. (Bambu sells the <a href="https://us.store.bambulab.com/products/p1s?variant=42153262743688">$699 P1S</a> for that.) And I did<em> </em>successfully use both the P1P and a pair of Creality K1 printers to produce dozens of objects over the past year, including pegboard mounts, figurines for my kids, and these badass unofficial Nerf blasters:</p>
<div id="bTXqzi"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12341356"></div></div>
<p id="z4cQbm">With either of these printers and a little knowledge of what’s easily 3D-printable, I can (<a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464309/20231205_094646__1_.jpg">sometimes</a>) send an entire plate full of parts to these printers and expect them to all turn out. </p>
<p id="Nrij7Z">But if you want fewer software and filament headaches, I would absolutely point you to Bambu. And I’d recommend you steer clear of the original Creality K1 entirely — I spent months struggling with issues that were instantly fixed when I swapped for the newer K1C model.</p>
<div>
<div id="zGB16j"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12340883"></div></div>
<div id="H6MssH"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12340891"></div></div>
</div>
<p id="BvSp8x">I took delivery of both the P1P and the original K1 last summer, and originally, I thought I’d be comparing both to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23612429/ankermake-m5-review-3d-printer">AnkerMake M5</a>. They’re all part of a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/4/13/23681219/anker-bambu-prusa-creality-3d-printer-speed-arms-race">recent wave of printers promising a huge increase in speed</a> and smarts. </p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xIcx5LEj0mLm8GyIWGxuIldGZMM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464000/bambu_3d_printed_side_panels.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>One of my first prints on the Bambu P1P: the white side panels it’s worn ever since.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="OM4Oea">But the Bambu P1P and Creality K1 series stood out as the most affordable full-size, full-featured <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CoreXY">CoreXY</a> printers that claim you can print right out of the box — with no need to bolt together a printer frame or even tighten belts. And while you can’t “just start printing the moment your K1 arrives,” as Creality puts it, both printers are mostly prebuilt, pretuned, and ready to go 20 or 30 minutes after you cut the packing tape. You remove a few safety pieces; attach their screens, power cables, and filament roll holders; connect to your home network for updates; and then press a button for automated setup. </p>
<p id="GjsZYC">Each will automatically level their bed so your prints literally get off on the right foot. They tune their motors with vibrations so intense, they shake the entire surface the printers are standing on. That’s intentional — because excess movement ruins prints, and printing quickly creates more movement, they teach themselves to avoid frequencies that rattle too hard. As I alluded to before, they both have <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CoreXY">CoreXY kinematics systems</a> that provide an incredibly speedy, stable bead of plastic without needing to sling your model back and forth on a moving bed. </p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AF3-aWtaViSa7p1mopwVGcHRliA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464262/core_xy_p1p_2.gif">
      <figcaption><em>With a CoreXY printer, the head moves in two dimensions while the bed slowly lowers, keeping the model stable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w4Uw30LRM3klQA1S-SnFrFEXRso=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464256/bedslinger_1.gif">
      <figcaption><em>Bedslingers, like this Bambu A1 Mini, fling the model one direction and the print head another.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="ntwGi2">But the next step is where the Bambu P1 and Creality K1 printers begin to diverge. When it’s time to stick your fishing line of consumable plastic into a Creality printer, you have to thread the needle, pushing a sharp point of plastic into a tube and through the extruder so that the hot nozzle can melt and squirt it out one tiny bead at a time. </p>
<p id="xeibKn">It’s the way many 3D printers have worked for years, but it leaves a lot of room for user error. It feels imprecise: you snip your filament at an angle to get a sharp point, then largely… shove until it feels right. Then you press a button and cross your fingers that the K1C’s motorized extruder will take it from there. Or manually shove it some more and hope the filament doesn’t break inside. Or you physically remove the filament tube, like I always did with my old Ender 3, so at least you can be sure you’re pushing straight down into the extruder without binding. </p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gO8xZX4LX6Y4zzcWQfrSR34YKK0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464311/20240323_165123.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>This Pikachu, made of silk PLA, came out pretty well on the K1C.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X9xvCt8MTtOMhu1raAUBFj7Ng18=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464312/20240323_165525.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Here it is with supports removed.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="EjjxOz">It could be worse! With the original K1, the filament pathway was so jam-prone that the company wound up designing and shipping <em>multiple</em> replacement parts during the time I had the printer, and even then, I had some trouble. With the K1C’s completely redesigned nozzles, I’ve mostly been able to shove filament in without issue.</p>
<p id="MHi9bP">But Bambu sidesteps all of that: there’s no needlepoint with a Bambu printer at all! Press a few buttons, insert uncut, flat-ended filament until you feel it being pulled away from your hand, and then, in my experience, it does the rest itself. The Bambu printer also automatically cuts off the molten bit when you’re ejecting filament, producing a nice clean-cut end I can effortlessly rewind without dragging on the printer’s internal parts. And, every single print, the Bambu purges that leftover molten filament into what owners have affectionately dubbed the “poop chute.” </p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qncy36y1_UtCs9F4iMRE9LHtHHc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464247/p1p_load.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The tiny non-touch screen is one of the few weaknesses of the Bambu P1P. I’m getting used to it.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="aJQ53t">The upshot: it took <em>months</em> before I saw my Bambu P1P jam for the first time. I’ve even had good results at times pushing old, brittle filament into Bambu printers. With the K1 and even K1C, it’s far less foolproof, as Creality makes you shove it through a filament runout sensor and a tight bend in the tubing before the extruder can grab it. I’ve broken the filament a couple of times in the K1C and many times in the original K1.</p>
<p id="4DFFim">And if you do have to get inside that extruder to fix or replace parts, Bambu makes it a breeze: its magnetic cover just lifts off, and $35 buys you <a href="https://us.store.bambulab.com/products/complete-hotend-assembly-p1p">a complete modular hotend</a> with heatsink, fan, heating element, and thermistor all attached — just two screws and a few easy cable pulls to swap it.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZFqeFc-o4TmkSjqhRBWLan2Y_DE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464275/p1p_cover.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Bambu’s magnetic cover pops off to reveal just two screws and two easy-pull connectors to remove the hotend.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4Z6CNOZtngtb1yiqB3-4w4wlVfg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464313/IMG_1796.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>To get inside Creality’s, you have to unscrew screws immediately underneath, and parallel to, the greased rails.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>

</div>
<p id="XlflRd">With Creality, there are five screws you have to remove at uncomfortable angles and a silicone sleeve that requires prying, and then you have to reach underneath to get at its tiny rear-facing connectors. You may even have to pull out a pair of pliers because the Creality assembly line inexplicably glues those connectors into place.</p>
<p id="HTWA1a">Mind you, you’re not going to be doing that every day or even every month: you generally only replace a nozzle if it wears out, gets badly jammed, or if you want to print at higher resolution for more detail or at lower resolution for more speed. For reference, I wound up replacing worn parts of my Ender 3 Pro’s hotend twice in three years after a series of messy jams. </p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eSGMzG5Jw9GV4qGp5rVwlfG7YOg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464015/creality_k1c_drip_near_part_fan.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Creality’s bed is a bit harder to clean and maintain... and whose idea was it to purge filament next to a fan intake?</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="kPVnCz">The last reason I think Bambu is a better choice for beginners is the print bed surface itself: how easily parts adhere and detach and how easy it is to clean. The Creality K1 series ships with a smooth PEI build plate that’s theoretically better for high temperature materials and initially gave my parts an incredibly smooth face. But it can be a challenge to remove some parts unless you apply a coating of the included glue stick (the kind kids use to paste paper together), and it’s easy to add too little or too much. I wound up tearing a chunk out of my build plate after too thin a coating. </p>
<p id="jB1cuE">Also, without a “poop chute,” I always found the K1 and K1C dripping tiny unwanted beads of plastic that’d wind up embedded in the bottom of models unless I carefully cleaned the print bed before each use. </p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/diCn2UcuvNJFsOOq_9Jsd7R28jo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464009/creality_bambu_Verge_Sean_Hollister_1_8.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>This should give you a good glimpse at the Bambu’s plate texture.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="NxZIgE">The P1P, meanwhile, ships with a textured PEI-covered stainless steel plate that’s almost never missed for me, no glue required. Generally, my parts are already loose by the time the bed cools. You can <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.creality.com%2Fproducts%2Fk1-pei-build-plate-kit&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F23924708%2Fcreality-k1c-bambu-p1p-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">buy such a plate for Creality, too</a>, though, and still be paying less than the P1P after you have both. </p>
<p id="JLFQx3">Not all of Creality’s K1C choices are worse for beginners! While its “AI camera” attaches to the printer at a slightly awkward angle, the timelapses it creates are much easier to monitor and download than the ones from Bambu’s camera. I appreciate the K1C’s simple twist-to-lock filament reel holder (Bambu uses screws), the USB port to load files (Bambu only gives you microSD), more reliable Wi-Fi, and of course, the large 4.3-inch color touchscreen. It’s so much easier to reprint a successful design or navigate a thumb drive when you can actually tap a picture of each design on a screen, instead of Up-Down-Left-Right navigating through Bambu’s small text-only interface. </p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rlGb0dQ_bffxU9XDzfWg3hM5K1Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464251/usb_k1c.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Creality’s K1C comes with a USB port and anti-vibration feet.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="Mj2egA">I also like that the Creality comes with anti-vibration feet, although, out of the box, my Bambu prints had more stable lines and steady surface textures even without them. The Bambu P1P is also quieter and can completely turn off its fans when idle. I’ve often come back to the Creality K1C after a day away and found it humming loudly in my garage.</p>
<p id="TNXJXr">Both companies need to work on their software, but Creality’s is definitely worse. While I’m having no real major trouble with Creality’s own Creality Print desktop app for basic 3D prints in PLA and flexible TPU plastic, I had major issues printing firmer and / or transparent PETG. It’s also missing loads of features compared to rival slicer apps you’d use to prepare your models for printing. (A slicer turns a 3D shape into printable horizontal layers and spits out code that tells the printer how to form each one.) </p>
<div id="xJT8o9"><div data-anthem-component="imageslider:12341749"></div></div>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bJmGKYWecQEPoQLAQmXn_o0Fqbs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464963/DSC02075.jpg">
      <figcaption>
<a class="ql-link" href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464963/DSC02075.jpg" target="_blank"><em>I had a easier time</em></a><em> making transparent green PETG appear transparent on the Bambu (left).</em>
</figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UPdodQfA_QZQ2_IW-V2llf-NYI8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464962/DSC02081.jpg">
      <figcaption>
<a class="ql-link" href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464962/DSC02081.jpg" target="_blank"><em>Another comparison</em></a><em> between P1P (left) and K1C (right) with the silver PETG. </em>
</figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="Wpe2du">You <em>can</em> use those rival slicers, but you may need to <a href="https://all3dp.com/2/best-creality-k1-cura-profile-settings/">tune them for your printer yourself</a> — some had even refused to support the K1 until Creality fulfilled obligations to open source its code. (<a href="https://forum.creality.com/t/creality-k1-series-creality-print-open-source-launch/5604">It seems Creality has now done so</a>.) <a href="https://github.com/SoftFever/OrcaSlicer/releases/tag/v1.9.0">OrcaSlicer</a> is a popular third-party alternative that does have its own K1 profile, and it helped me print in PETG when Creality Print wouldn’t.</p>
<p id="a879R5">Creality’s mobile app, meanwhile, is gamified to the point that I want nothing to do with it. I just want a way to start and monitor prints, not earn points for printing trendy junk! I even had to turn off app notifications after I got bombarded with point earning opportunities each day, though it seems the company’s cut back on the notifications since launch.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bEG5Nr_pmw1dAU0_N0y8nWaZGas=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25464301/bambu_mouse_fail.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The failed print I’m talking about: it’s for a wireless mouse.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="vveMEX">But while Bambu’s slicer is great and its app doesn’t have the same annoyances, I’m not entirely sure I can trust the company’s cloud. One month after the company’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23837180/bambu-rogue-3d-printers-fix-cloud-outage">very good apology for its rogue printer incident</a>, I had a similar issue. I went out to the garage one morning to find a model I’d printed directly from its cloud half-finished, stuck to my nozzle, with a <em>second</em> halfway printed copy of the model on the floor. </p>
<p id="B5Vagq">I’ve tried to print a few other models from its new MakerWorld, a place where you can supposedly find one-click prints validated to work on Bambu’s specific printers, no slicing or tweaks necessary, but one became a huge hunk of worthless plastic because it actually wasn’t validated. I guess I could always go with <a href="https://wiki.bambulab.com/en/knowledge-sharing/enable-lan-mode">a private LAN-only connection</a> to the printer instead of using the cloud.</p>
<p id="XPZh3b">It doesn’t take a lot of imagination to see from here to an even easier 3D printing future. Bambu’s new A1 series printers now have completely tool-less hotend swaps — <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/20/23881523/bambu-a1-mini-ams-lite-3d-printer-price-release-hands-on#:~:text=the%20entire%20hotend%20can%20be%20hot%2Dswapped%20without%20any%20tools">just pop the pieces off</a>. The company’s working on new sensors that can detect when your filament <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/20/23881523/bambu-a1-mini-ams-lite-3d-printer-price-release-hands-on#:~:text=Lots%20of%20strain%20on%20that%20filament.">tangles while it’s still on the roll</a>, something that occasionally trips up every 3D printer I’ve yet used. I’ve also yet to see a 3D printer company ship their printers with a dry box to keep moisture out of their filament, but Creality does sell them separately, and it’s definitely something they could do to get us closer to that push-button, get-object future! </p>
<p id="SrwNOi">(I’m not saying you should buy an A1: I had more jams and lower-quality results <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/20/23881523/bambu-a1-mini-ams-lite-3d-printer-price-release-hands-on#:~:text=for%20my%20purposes.-,With%20PLA,-%2C%20I%E2%80%99m%20mostly%20noticing">with an A1 Mini than my P1P</a>, the filament tangle detection still doesn’t work, and many things I print are too big for its bed. I haven’t gotten to test the full-size A1 since <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/4/24061794/bambu-lab-a1-3d-printer-recall-heatbed-cable-damage">its recall</a>.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wwmTJ1hgLOxfvYoHK4uVS_nQmUQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25463994/creality_bambu_Verge_Sean_Hollister_1_7.jpg">
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="jzVywI">The biggest way 3D printers will earn trust, though, is if companies like Creality and Bambu stop shipping them before they’re ready. I can’t believe the terrible state the original Creality K1 first shipped in, and if you lurk in the right places on Reddit and Discord, you’ll hear veterans say that the Bambu P1P shipped with early issues, too. And I’ve read <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BambuLab/comments/174eo72/bambu_lab_keep_sending_me_broken_printers/">plenty</a> of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BambuLab/comments/16hd50h/bambu_x1c_printer_broken_on_arrival_support/">testimonials</a> from Bambu customers who, like me with the Creality K1, were expected to open up their printers to fix broken things instead of sending them in for service. It’s a good reminder that these are hobbyist devices, not consumer products, even as these companies talk about democratizing 3D printing for everyone.   </p>
<p class="c-end-para" id="TDw37c">No matter which printer you’re eyeing, I strongly recommend steering clear of ones that have just launched. Wait for early adopters to iron things out! But if you’re itching to get printing, I’m pretty happy with the nearly two-year-old P1P. </p>
<p id="TVKp7e"><em>Photography by Sean Hollister / The Verge</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/23924708/creality-k1c-bambu-p1p-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/23924708/creality-k1c-bambu-p1p-review</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ventje turns VW’s ID Buzz into a very charming e-camper]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="A customized ID Buzz Ventje sits on the grass beneath the trees with the pop-top and tail gate open and furniture setup on the lawn." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pkHDTXboq6jd5URgDfbDo39EwqU=/0x207:5712x4015/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73370636/IMG_4990.0.jpeg" />
        <figcaption><em>Ventje’s eVentje.</em></figcaption>
    </figure>


  <p>The eVentje custom buildout is a worthy all-electric successor to the iconic VW Camper.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Wzeq4S">Volkswagen’s ID Buzz now has a custom camper build-out that’s just as clever and charming as the electric microbus. It’s called <a href="https://ventje.com/en/articles/eventje/">eVentje</a>, and it’s now available for general sale in Europe.</p>
<p id="Edg1qf">Designed and sold by <a href="https://ventje.com/en/">Ventje</a>, a small but rapidly growing company based in the Netherlands, the eVentje conversion is as good as it gets until VW finally releases a California edition of the ID Buzz — which is still a few years away at least. That long delay since European sales began in 2022 has made room for a burgeoning aftermarket for ID Buzz camper products, including the excellent and relatively inexpensive <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23735554/vw-id-buzz-review-ququq-camper-e-vanlife">Ququq camping box</a> I previously reviewed.</p>
<p id="CV1RPG">I <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23203408/ventje-frank-westland-review-price">first tested a Ventje camper</a> built on top of a VW Transporter T5 cargo van in 2022, before <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23735554/vw-id-buzz-review-ququq-camper-e-vanlife">living and working from an ID Buzz</a> for a few weeks in 2023. In 2024, I finally got to test the union of the two for a weekend. And let me tell you, this is definitely a case where the whole is greater than the sum of its parts. The ID Buzz has always been a showstopper when driving past onlookers — now, the show continues when the doors open to reveal that wonderfully adaptive Ventje interior.</p>
<div id="bZutqf">
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C7ZN80JsTYL/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C7ZN80JsTYL/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"> <div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div> <div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><svg width="50px" height="50px" viewbox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"><g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;"> <div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;"> <div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div></a><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C7ZN80JsTYL/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by The Verge (@verge)</a></p>
</div></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>
</div>
<p id="TfH9rz">The overall design of the Ventje camper still relies on more than 100 magnets to keep all those wooden surfaces aligned and locked in place. There’s still a kitchen accessible from inside and out, a pop-top tent, and a multipurpose interior that converts from a lounge to a bed to a luxurious outside furniture set in minutes. Only now, things have been refined throughout with one big addition: a folding table and hidden stools to create an outside bar. <em>Swoon</em>.</p>
<p id="ZPCQQl">The kitchen has seen several improvements that provide more adaptable prep surfaces — always a challenge in a small space — and smarter use of storage. Ventje also moved to not one but two induction cooktops thanks to the inclusion of a 2200W inverter and 2160Wh leisure battery that charges from the VW’s driving battery, a 350-watt solar panel, and a mini shore-power outlet located on the lower backside of the van.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid__wrapper">
<div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/szVPlCP49lYS9iamJ85km6aJZV0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25450779/IMG_5608.jpeg">
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hSJlj6uOMnNFKAgOeify9LztiuA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25450782/IMG_5545.jpeg">
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QAwL2I0JOn3_y9h01G-7TuLeyLA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25450784/IMG_3500.jpeg">
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LNnJAd47qh75-qHKlRZag1DuDJk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25450786/IMG_4913.jpeg">
  </figure>
</div>
</div>
<p class="caption"><em>There’s even a bar.</em></p>
</div></div>
<p id="MREzAQ">Ventje also makes it easier to keep all your own gear powered with eight USB sockets (4x USB-A, 4x USB-C), a 12V car jack, 3x wireless charging surfaces, and 3x 230V AC sockets for anyone looking to take advantage of their company’s hybrid office policy. There are also more lighting options including dimmable LED light strips and a closable sunroof in the pop-top tent.</p>
<p id="HJrWvn">VW’s poorly designed software still frustrates the otherwise exceptional driving experience, which remains rattle-free even with all of Ventje’s customizations. One would expect VW to eventually enable a camping mode on the ID Buzz, a feature already found on its existing California series campers. That would make heating and cooling the ID Buzz more intuitive when parked and allow owners to more easily disable the interior motion alarm when locking all the doors at night. </p>
<p id="hkGv2i">The eVentje can sleep four but is currently highway legal for only two people. It’s built around the regular-wheelbase ID Buzz, not the long-wheelbase model coming to Europe and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/13/24155355/vw-id-buzz-us-trim-powertrain-details-launch-first-edition">the US (finally!) later this year</a>. Nevertheless, my wife and I didn’t want for more space, even with the dog coming along on the trip. </p>
<div id="kft0ts"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12334540"></div></div>
<p id="evAkUS">The eVentje, like the ID Buzz, isn’t cheap, and soon, in Europe, it will have to compete with <a href="https://www.volkswagen-nutzfahrzeuge.de/de/modelle/california.html">VW’s new PHEV “T7” California camper</a> going on sale in June for what’s probably about the same price. But that model lacks the retrofuturistic appeal of the all-electric ID Buzz, and its interior is arguably less flexible — and definitely less fun — than Ventje’s warm custom design.</p>
<p id="KArI2C">The modified eVentje ID Buzz starts at €95,000 (about $103,000) in Europe. An order placed today will ship in nine months to customers in the Netherlands, Belgium, France, Germany, Switzerland, Spain, Denmark, Sweden, and Norway. Ventje says that it’s also planning to expand to the UK and US in time. </p>
<p id="MgsXHg">Importantly, Ventje is doing what VW hasn’t since <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/19/16173938/volkswagen-microbus-i-d-buzz-concept-production-nostalgia">first teasing the ID Buzz all the way back in 2017</a>: deliver a worthy all-electric successor to the iconic Type 2 camper.</p>
<p id="4lhBnl"><em>Photography by Thomas Ricker / The Verge</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24158082/id-buzz-ventje-camper-review-price-specs</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24158082/id-buzz-ventje-camper-review-price-specs</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ventje turns VW’s ID Buzz into a very charming e-camper]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="A customized ID Buzz Ventje sits on the grass beneath the trees with the pop-top and tail gate open and furniture setup on the lawn." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pkHDTXboq6jd5URgDfbDo39EwqU=/0x207:5712x4015/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73370636/IMG_4990.0.jpeg" />
        <figcaption><em>Ventje’s eVentje.</em></figcaption>
    </figure>


  <p>The eVentje custom buildout is a worthy all-electric successor to the iconic VW Camper.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Wzeq4S">Volkswagen’s ID Buzz now has a custom camper build-out that’s just as clever and charming as the electric microbus. It’s called <a href="https://ventje.com/en/articles/eventje/">eVentje</a>, and it’s now available for general sale in Europe.</p>
<p id="Edg1qf">Designed and sold by <a href="https://ventje.com/en/">Ventje</a>, a small but rapidly growing company based in the Netherlands, the eVentje conversion is as good as it gets until VW finally releases a California edition of the ID Buzz — which is still a few years away at least. That long delay since European sales began in 2022 has made room for a burgeoning aftermarket for ID Buzz camper products, including the excellent and relatively inexpensive <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23735554/vw-id-buzz-review-ququq-camper-e-vanlife">Ququq camping box</a> I previously reviewed.</p>
<p id="CV1RPG">I <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23203408/ventje-frank-westland-review-price">first tested a Ventje camper</a> built on top of a VW Transporter T5 cargo van in 2022, before <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23735554/vw-id-buzz-review-ququq-camper-e-vanlife">living and working from an ID Buzz</a> for a few weeks in 2023. In 2024, I finally got to test the union of the two for a weekend. And let me tell you, this is definitely a case where the whole is greater than the sum of its parts. The ID Buzz has always been a showstopper when driving past onlookers — now, the show continues when the doors open to reveal that wonderfully adaptive Ventje interior.</p>
<div id="bZutqf">
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C7ZN80JsTYL/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C7ZN80JsTYL/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"> <div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div> <div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><svg width="50px" height="50px" viewbox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"><g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;"> <div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;"> <div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div></a><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C7ZN80JsTYL/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by The Verge (@verge)</a></p>
</div></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>
</div>
<p id="TfH9rz">The overall design of the Ventje camper still relies on more than 100 magnets to keep all those wooden surfaces aligned and locked in place. There’s still a kitchen accessible from inside and out, a pop-top tent, and a multipurpose interior that converts from a lounge to a bed to a luxurious outside furniture set in minutes. Only now, things have been refined throughout with one big addition: a folding table and hidden stools to create an outside bar. <em>Swoon</em>.</p>
<p id="ZPCQQl">The kitchen has seen several improvements that provide more adaptable prep surfaces — always a challenge in a small space — and smarter use of storage. Ventje also moved to not one but two induction cooktops thanks to the inclusion of a 2200W inverter and 2160Wh leisure battery that charges from the VW’s driving battery, a 350-watt solar panel, and a mini shore-power outlet located on the lower backside of the van.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid__wrapper">
<div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/szVPlCP49lYS9iamJ85km6aJZV0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25450779/IMG_5608.jpeg">
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hSJlj6uOMnNFKAgOeify9LztiuA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25450782/IMG_5545.jpeg">
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QAwL2I0JOn3_y9h01G-7TuLeyLA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25450784/IMG_3500.jpeg">
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LNnJAd47qh75-qHKlRZag1DuDJk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25450786/IMG_4913.jpeg">
  </figure>
</div>
</div>
<p class="caption"><em>There’s even a bar.</em></p>
</div></div>
<p id="MREzAQ">Ventje also makes it easier to keep all your own gear powered with eight USB sockets (4x USB-A, 4x USB-C), a 12V car jack, 3x wireless charging surfaces, and 3x 230V AC sockets for anyone looking to take advantage of their company’s hybrid office policy. There are also more lighting options including dimmable LED light strips and a closable sunroof in the pop-top tent.</p>
<p id="HJrWvn">VW’s poorly designed software still frustrates the otherwise exceptional driving experience, which remains rattle-free even with all of Ventje’s customizations. One would expect VW to eventually enable a camping mode on the ID Buzz, a feature already found on its existing California series campers. That would make heating and cooling the ID Buzz more intuitive when parked and allow owners to more easily disable the interior motion alarm when locking all the doors at night. </p>
<p id="hkGv2i">The eVentje can sleep four but is currently highway legal for only two people. It’s built around the regular-wheelbase ID Buzz, not the long-wheelbase model coming to Europe and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/13/24155355/vw-id-buzz-us-trim-powertrain-details-launch-first-edition">the US (finally!) later this year</a>. Nevertheless, my wife and I didn’t want for more space, even with the dog coming along on the trip. </p>
<div id="kft0ts"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12334540"></div></div>
<p id="evAkUS">The eVentje, like the ID Buzz, isn’t cheap, and soon, in Europe, it will have to compete with <a href="https://www.volkswagen-nutzfahrzeuge.de/de/modelle/california.html">VW’s new PHEV “T7” California camper</a> going on sale in June for what’s probably about the same price. But that model lacks the retrofuturistic appeal of the all-electric ID Buzz, and its interior is arguably less flexible — and definitely less fun — than Ventje’s warm custom design.</p>
<p id="KArI2C">The modified eVentje ID Buzz starts at €95,000 (about $103,000) in Europe. An order placed today will ship in nine months to customers in the Netherlands, Belgium, France, Germany, Switzerland, Spain, Denmark, Sweden, and Norway. Ventje says that it’s also planning to expand to the UK and US in time. </p>
<p id="MgsXHg">Importantly, Ventje is doing what VW hasn’t since <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/19/16173938/volkswagen-microbus-i-d-buzz-concept-production-nostalgia">first teasing the ID Buzz all the way back in 2017</a>: deliver a worthy all-electric successor to the iconic Type 2 camper.</p>
<p id="4lhBnl"><em>Photography by Thomas Ricker / The Verge</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24158082/id-buzz-ventje-camper-review-price-specs</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24158082/id-buzz-ventje-camper-review-price-specs</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[EcoFlow’s $200 PowerStream is so clever, you might buy a $4,000 solar generator ]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>A mini power plant that turns a standard power outlet into a solar power inlet.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="HlDGO1">Portable <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Atheverge.com%20solar%20generator">solar generators</a> are so useful that you increasingly see them at the beach, campground, job site, or anywhere without access to grid power. But they’re also an expensive luxury if shoved into storage as soon as you return home.</p>
<p class="p-large-text" id="Mhb5io"><a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Feu.ecoflow.com%2Fpages%2Fpowerstream&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24150901%2Fecoflow-powerstream-review-diy-balcony-solar-microinverter" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">EcoFlow’s $200-ish PowerStream box</a> can help maximize the year-round usefulness of the company’s own solar generators. It’s pitched as a plug-in “balcony solar system” that anyone can install, even if you’re renting an apartment. </p>
<p id="smCUUe">These DIY systems from EcoFlow, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/14/23760241/anker-solix-home-energy-solution-system-announce">Anker</a>, and <a href="https://we.do.solar">others</a> became <a href="https://www.euronews.com/green/2024/04/21/solar-balconies-are-booming-in-germany-heres-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-popular-home-">very popular</a> around Europe over the last few years as energy costs soared amid steadily decreasing solar and battery prices. They can lower your energy bills and ensure a modicum of home backup in the event of a power outage. </p>
<p id="4K5Rra">Plug-in systems are built around a microinverter that feeds solar energy back into the home via a standard wall jack. The solar panels can be leaned up against a terrace wall, placed in a garden, or hung off a balcony railing<em>. </em>Any solar excess not used immediately by the home can be diverted into the solar generator’s big-ass battery for use later. </p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LfoeAWtRvWyNSmaH3a6hQgf5rbc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462810/c86a8d8936024ea8908ff5cb59a1e90e_ezgif.com_video_to_gif_converter.gif">
      <cite>Image: EcoFlow</cite>
      <figcaption>
<em>Balcony-mounted solar panels feed the sun’s energy through the PowerStream microinverter and back into a battery and / or the home over a regular AC outlet. A special flat cable allows the window to close.</em> GIF: EcoFlow </figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="LYtvoX">I’ve been testing an EcoFlow PowerStream setup in my own home, where I’ve installed $1,500 worth of EcoFlow’s portable solar panels on my roof, with the cables snaking through a window to the PowerStream box connected to a $2,599 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23334052/ecoflow-delta-pro-battery-review-rv-off-grid-price">EcoFlow Delta Pro</a>. I also have six EcoFlow smart plugs attached to things like the washing machine, coffee maker, and home theater projector that tell the PowerStream to send more or less power.</p>
<p id="1MU0HD">It’s surprisingly simple to set up and get running, but not without some initial trepidation about safety, which I delve into below. I also made a mistake that killed the first PowerStream EcoFlow sent me. But importantly, I learned a lot about my family’s energy consumption habits and how much power 800W of haphazardly installed solar panels can produce under a weak northern sun.</p>
<p id="3CPbdH">So, it’s a shame that EcoFlow’s PowerStream is a Europe-only solution for now.</p>
<div><div id="P7saBL"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12327114"></div></div></div>
<h2 id="iGmYkm">How does it save me money?</h2>
<p id="YetaGg">The PowerStream has three proprietary ports: one that connects to your MC4 solar panels; one that connects to your battery; and one AC output that plugs into a standard wall socket. The battery is entirely optional if you just want to feed every watt of solar power produced back into your home.</p>
<p id="cI6397">To understand how the PowerStream works, let’s look at a real example using screen recordings taken from the excellent EcoFlow app. Note how the direction of power delivery changes from GIF to GIF as EcoFlow’s smart plugs steadily increase demand.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_AoiIFXKxUsq2C7NUp0LAG-G4Gw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452434/gif1_small_wide.gif">
      <figcaption><em>The home is demanding less power than my solar panels are producing, so the excess solar energy is diverted to the battery for use later.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="mfhtea">In the first GIF above, I’m generating 397W of solar power, but my home is only demanding 290W — 250W for the “base load” and 40W for EcoFlow’s smart plugs (both of which I’ll describe in detail later). Since that load could be covered by solar power alone, the PowerStream didn’t need to request any power from the grid. It immediately sends the excess 107W of solar to charge the connected Delta Pro battery instead.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wfKGeyIoqiOG_TiP2atXF9iWWKY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452435/gif2_small_wide.gif">
      <figcaption><em>Turning on the home theater projector increases demand beyond what the solar panels can provide, so the PowerStream taps into the battery to make up the balance.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="3YHvCR">But after I turn on my home theater projector, the “smart plug” load jumps to 239W, and my solar panels can no longer cover the 489W now demanded by my home. So PowerStream diverts an extra 92W from the battery to cover the new total. Power grid demand is still 0W since the incoming solar power and battery power can cover the total demand of the home.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mn4Gfl4mvcxZt6UXTbMoKuhqB9U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452436/gif3_small_wide.gif">
      <figcaption><em>Turning on the Nespresso coffee machine exceeds the 800W capacity of the PowerStream, so the grid is called upon to provide the rest.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="jmxNRm">Finally, I turn on my Nespresso coffee machine, which activates the grid. The PowerStream has a maximum output of 800W (805W in this example), so it pulls an extra 845W from my grid provider to cover the 1,650W (1.4K plus 250W) my home is now demanding.</p>
<p id="Oehvou">Pretty clever, right? </p>
<p id="A44zNC">And while batteries do degrade if you cycle them every day like this, the LFP chemistry used by modern solar generators like the Delta Pro should maintain 80 percent of its charging capacity after 3,500 cycles — that’s almost 10 years. And it should still be good for 50 percent capacity after 6,000 cycles.</p>
<p id="cCYi7g">By the end of my example day, the PowerStream had produced a total of 3.03kWh, saving me a grand total of... 90 euro cents at my current energy rates. That might not sound like a lot, but at that rate, it will easily pay off the PowerStream after about a year of usage — faster in some climates and slower in others. Notably, it would have paid itself off in just months last year, when I was paying over three times as much per kWh due to global events.</p>
<div><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GFAIZdlU-JWgEonYIQ7NC-BKxgE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25436759/IMG_4744.jpeg">
      <figcaption><em>Solar power from the PowerStream on April 29th. Note production peaking between 11AM and 3PM.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BKrl0ftsUjBKuu_vafTor4VxYTE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25436758/IMG_4566.jpeg">
      <figcaption><em>Power from my grid provider, also on April 29th, 2024. My paid energy usage is mostly zero from 11AM to 3PM, and overall usage is well below 2023.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="8wvywz">Importantly, I have gained a degree of energy independence in this uncertain world — and making regular use of an expensive solar generator that was otherwise just waiting for the next road trip or natural disaster. </p>
<p id="doLsUW">Great, but is feeding that much electricity into a standard wall socket actually safe?</p>
<h2 id="nQNlkI"><strong>A power outlet becomes a power inlet</strong></h2>
<p id="pQG9Do">It might seem odd and even unsafe to feed electricity into something called a <em>power outlet</em>, but AC wall jacks are, in fact, bidirectional under the right conditions.</p>
<p id="rRGTCm">The PowerStream is a mini power plant that automatically synchronizes with the grid to ensure seamless integration with the devices plugged into your home circuitry. Power flows from high to low voltages, which is why the grid voltage is slightly higher (by millivolts) than the devices plugged in. The PowerStream similarly alters its voltage to regulate the flow of power to your devices.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qYqMB6gdMohwa4TCgsNaIgtiFLM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25438639/IMG_4869.jpeg">
      <figcaption><em>EcoFlow’s smart plug works with the PowerStream to control the flow of power.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="m0xSeR">EcoFlow says that PowerStream is not a burden on 16A home circuits in Europe because it’s limited to a maximum of 800W (or 600W in Germany, currently) and requires less than 3.5A. PowerStream has obtained grid certification in over 10 countries, covering 70 percent of Europe. You might still have to register it with your local energy provider, however — so do check your local requirements. </p>
<p id="oeHG6S">And when there’s a power outage, the PowerStream will turn off automatically to ensure there’s no electricity in the wires in order to protect line workers from shock. The PowerStream will only turn back on when the grid power returns. </p>
<p id="ABuid7">(This also means that the PowerStream, unlike a Tesla Powerwall or EcoFlow’s own <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/9/23996517/ecoflow-delta-pro-ultra-solar-generator-home-backup-price-specs">Delta Pro Ultra</a> home backup system, can’t automatically switch over to battery during a blackout to power the home. Instead you have to disconnect the battery — a 100-pound Delta Pro in my case — from the PowerSteam and wheel it to wherever power is needed, like the kitchen or basement.)</p>
<p id="xwxWzY">Despite how it looks in the app, the PowerStream isn’t actually sending power <em>directly</em> to the devices attached to those EcoFlow smart plugs. The PowerStream uses the smart plugs as signals to pump more or less juice into the stream of power entering the home, from which every device can drink.</p>
<p id="HYYKqb">Microinverters like EcoFlow’s PowerStream aren’t available in the US at all due to restrictions that prohibit plug-in grid solutions.</p>
<h2 id="h5Z87H"><strong>Installation</strong></h2>
<p id="KNPQa8">The hardest part in setting up the PowerStream is doing the math to ensure your solar panels are wired up properly in <a href="https://blog.ecoflow.com/ca/wiring-solar-panels-parallel-vs-series/">series or parallel</a>, especially when maxing out the system like I did. My bad math caused me to smoke the first PowerStream review unit by overvolting it (where, by “smoke,” I mean it just stopped working forever). Eventually, I figured out the right wiring configuration to keep everything under the 55V / 13A limit of the PowerStream’s solar inputs. </p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6uwba0sAK6eB3Q14F8yF1d3_GI0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25436854/IMG_4753__2_.jpeg">
      <figcaption><em>800W of portable solar panels takes up a ton of space.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="ejqS7H">My setup is meant to be temporary because I still want to take the portable EcoFlow solar panels and Delta Pro on the road — but those panels need to be securely mounted. This can be done using EcoFlow’s own mounts (or your own, like I did) because a strong wind could easily send those lightweight panels flying. Of course, there’s nothing preventing you from connecting a PowerStream to rigid panels from any company you choose.</p>
<p id="xtKIet">EcoFlow also sells its <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Feu.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fpowerstream-balcony-solar-system-waterproof-battery-series-600-w-800-w%3Fvariant%3D47818187276631&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24150901%2Fecoflow-powerstream-review-diy-balcony-solar-microinverter" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">PowerStream with a new waterproof battery</a> for a super tidy outdoor installation. Everything, including the PowerStream, is IP54 rated, and the 2kWh battery is even heated to ensure proper operation in temperatures down to -20 degrees Celsius (-4 degrees Fahrenheit). The kit runs completely silently, as does the PowerStream in my own comparatively crude installation.</p>
<p id="kW3B2n">With all the hardware installed, you then need to decide whether to prioritize power delivery from the PowerStream to your home circuitry or to battery storage. I currently default to home but would switch that to battery if a storm were in the forecast to ensure I had backup power. While you can schedule these modes to change throughout the day, you can only do it based on time, which is a shame. Ideally, it would automatically prioritize the battery if a big storm were in the forecast, as many home backup systems do.</p>
<p id="nbzkTo">Still, scheduling a change in priority modes can be very useful if you’re on a variable energy contract. That way, you can charge the battery during off-peak hours and then use that relatively cheap stored energy to power the home when electricity prices are highest.</p>
<div id="BF2E7Z"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12327082"></div></div>
<p id="bJ720u">The real trick to optimizing the PowerStream is to first determine your home’s idle baseline power usage — how many watts your home continuously pulls before turning on things like the dishwasher or coffee maker. Mine’s about 300W, according to the display on the smart energy meter in my utility closet. Ideally, EcoFlow’s PowerStream would get real-time readings from my smart meter, but that’s not currently possible.</p>
<p id="DmUcz3">So, I set what EcoFlow calls the base load to 250W in its app to ensure a 50W cushion. That way, I can avoid feeding energy back into the grid. Doing so has potential financial repercussions depending on your provider and where you live. As the sun returns here in the Netherlands, power companies are struggling to cope with oversupply under the current solar incentive scheme, resulting in charges levied against panel owners for energy returned to the grid. </p>
<h2 id="IwN4Fx">EcoFlow smart plugs help direct traffic</h2>
<p id="0FdWUh">Some PowerStream installations will benefit from a handful of Matter-enabled <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Feu.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fsmart-plug%3F_pos%3D1%26_sid%3D5dba68d2e%26_ss%3Dr%26variant%3D46928801268055&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24150901%2Fecoflow-powerstream-review-diy-balcony-solar-microinverter" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">EcoFlow smart plugs</a> installed on high-consumption devices like the TV, washer, dryer, dishwasher, refrigerator, and boiler to properly balance the load. They tell the PowerStream that those devices are demanding even more power than the base load, so it needs to ramp things up. Each smart plug costs €36 (about $39).</p>
<p id="RoiTEy">In the first screen recording below, you can see the PowerStream delivering 482W into the home. It determines this number by starting with the 250W I set as my base load and adding 232W to cover all the devices connected to the smart plugs. And since only 355W was coming in via solar at the time, it pulls an additional 127W from the connected Delta Pro battery for the home. In the second recording, the excess solar power is immediately diverted to the battery now that the projector is turned off.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qax0WSuMj9v_Imd0V4QDdJje07E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25436762/Powerstreamsolarpower.gif">
      <figcaption><em>The PowerStream, with help from EcoFlow’s smart plugs, senses that my home needs more power than solar is producing, so it taps the battery for an additional 126W.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L5k1mSJJ0ryQzXBHs4LuJh4mmtk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25436763/powerstreampowerbatteryandhome.gif">
      <figcaption><em>The PowerStream senses a surplus of energy being produced by the solar panels, so it diverts the excess 74W to charge the battery.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="Y7jVub">And while the app shows the power grid delivering 0W into the home, this is pure fantasy since I don’t have smart plugs on every single device attached to my home. (And remember, my true baseline is closer to 300W.) </p>
<p id="tGbGQq">More power-heavy homes can just skip the smart plugs entirely. My maxed-out system with 800W of solar input can only generate a maximum of 4kWh per day, usually much less. That’s not enough to cover my daily base load of 6kWh (250W x 24 hours). So I should just feed enough solar power into the home to cover my base load during the day and send any excess to the EcoFlow battery for use when the sun goes down.</p>
<p class="p--has-dropcap" id="7eoIE4">I have to say, I’m incredibly impressed by the PowerStream, especially now that it’s <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Feu.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fpowerstream-microinverter&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24150901%2Fecoflow-powerstream-review-diy-balcony-solar-microinverter" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">priced at just €150</a>, almost half off the €279 it cost at launch last year. Not only does it help existing owners of EcoFlow’s solar generators maximize the value for their money but it also makes the idea of owning a solar generator more tempting knowing you can use it year-round, at home or off the grid. </p>
<p id="bMWwiP">It also makes the owner acutely aware of their energy habits. I’ve been obsessing over the EcoFlow app’s data like a new runner who just bought their first Garmin watch. For me, it’s been an interesting and relatively frugal first step toward energy independence. I now have real data and experience to help make a very complex decision about installing my own fixed panel system.</p>
<p id="OIoau2"><em>Photography by Thomas Ricker / The Verge</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24150901/ecoflow-powerstream-review-diy-balcony-solar-microinverter</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24150901/ecoflow-powerstream-review-diy-balcony-solar-microinverter</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 05:35:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8A review: the sensible choice]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>At $499 with all the essential features, Google’s Pixel phone starts making sense.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="OZ9brB">Hear me out: out of Google’s entire Pixel lineup, the A-series budget phone makes the most sense. </p>
<p id="ppPhW5">Sure, the Pixel 8A misses out on the fancier stuff, like a telephoto lens or the very highest rating for water resistance. It doesn’t fold in half. But it has two things working in its favor: time and money.</p>
<p id="SyDkfD">The Pixel 8A arrives six months after <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23912370/google-pixel-8-pro-review-camera-assistant-magic-editor-best-take-audio-eraser">the Pixel 8 and 8 Pro</a>, which works to its advantage. That’s enough time to let <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/24/24048920/google-pixel-bug-internal-storage-access-crashing-apps">some of the early bugs shake out</a> on the new OS and the dust settle on issues like “Which of these phones get on-device AI and which don’t?” Google eventually arrived at the correct answer a few months ago, which is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/28/24114078/google-pixel-8-gemini-nano-on-device-ai">all of them</a> — Pixel 8A included.</p>
<p id="aE5ioo">As for the money, the Pixel 8A starts at only $499 in the time of $1,000 flagship phones. When you consider that it has almost all of the core features of the $799 Pixel 8, it starts looking like even more of a bargain. And with seven years of software updates promised? It’s hard to beat that kind of ROI.</p>
<div><div id="MtO6Sf"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12338800"></div></div></div>
<p id="OiOR2d">The Pixel 8A comes with a sturdy aluminum frame and Gorilla Glass 3 on the front panel, like the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23716677/google-pixel-7a-review-screen-camera-battery">7A</a>. The plastic back panel has a frosty matte finish, and I have great news about the new aloe color option: it rules. The 8A is rated IP67, meaning it’s totally dustproof and resistant to a brief dip in shallow water. That’s not too common in this class, and it’s a cut above the OnePlus 12R’s mere splash resistance. </p>
<p id="ipR9NK">I spent a few busy travel days using the Pixel 8A and never once had to think about the battery. Even with a lot more social media scrolling than usual, plus navigation and Uber rides, the battery still had plenty in the tank by the end of the day. Like its predecessor, the 8A comes with Qi wireless charging. I love to drop my phone onto a charging stand at the end of the day, and most budget phones won’t let you do this.</p>
<p id="46uqAY">This year’s screen has been upgraded to a top refresh rate of 120Hz, matching the Pixel 8 and 8 Pro. Motion on the screen like scrolling and animations looks much smoother than on a standard 60Hz or even the 90Hz screen on the 7A, so this feels like an update with real impact. It’s a 6.1-inch 1080p OLED, and it’s not the very best screen in the class — that belongs to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24072383/oneplus-12r-review-screen-camera-price">the OnePlus 12R</a>. But the 8A’s display feels at least good enough in the era of high refresh rate screens.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><div id="H9Kz0z"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12339545"></div></div></div>
<p id="VFTA6n">The Pixel 8A uses Google’s Tensor G3 chipset, as seen in the Pixel 8 and 8 Pro, coupled with 8GB of RAM — the same as the Pixel 8. That’s apparently enough to run Gemini Nano, Google’s mobile-optimized AI model, on-device, though you’ll have to switch it on as a developer preview option. Google limited this capability to the Pixel 8 Pro at first but <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/28/24114078/google-pixel-8-gemini-nano-on-device-ai">later corrected course</a>. </p>
<p id="u6AjFd">Right now, Gemini Nano lets a couple of AI features happen on-device, meaning you don’t need an internet connection and your data remains private. Right now, it’s limited to summaries for recordings and Magic Compose in Messages to change the tone of your writing. </p>
<p id="SNpfzF">Not very impressive at the moment, but Google claims it will <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://store.google.com/intl/en/ideas/articles/gemini-nano-google-pixel/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">expand on-device capabilities with Gemini Nano</a> later this year, including a feature that alerts you when a caller might be trying to scam you. Better to have it than not, and the Pixel 8A will be one of the least expensive phones with on-device AI capabilities when that option becomes available. In the meantime, the Pixel 8A handled all of my day-to-day tasks without any problems. </p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="Google Pixel 8A showing homescreen." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9bUq32u3IUwrNi3aoO4nnwYVZ1c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451801/DSC07458_processed.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The 8A is ready for on-device AI.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="pHz49Y">I’m happy to see that the Pixel 8A comes with one of the best quality-of-life updates from the Pixel 8 and 8 Pro: the ability to use face unlock for mobile payments and password managers. On previous Pixel phones, you could unlock your phone with your face, but if you wanted to pay for a latte, you’d have to verify again with your fingerprint. </p>
<p id="kIWIB8">It sounds like I’m making a lot out of a little thing, and maybe I am, but it just makes using the phone feel much more seamless. I don’t have to readjust my grip or set down whatever I’m holding in my other hand to verify my password manager; it just happens, and I appreciate it.</p>
<div id="CA4vlx"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12339566"></div></div>
<p id="ofmP2U">For day-to-day use, I think you’d have a hard time telling the Pixel 8A apart from the 8 or 8 Pro, but the differences are easier to spot when you switch to the camera app. There are two rear cameras, both carried over from the Pixel 7A, and for a budget phone, they’re quite good. </p>
<p id="4BstbV">The main 64-megapixel camera offers optical image stabilization to help fend off blur from low-light shots, and there’s a capable 13-megapixel ultrawide. You don’t get a video portrait mode or macro mode, and you definitely don’t get a dedicated telephoto camera — those are scarce on budget phones, anyway.</p>
<div id="lKDMIx"><div data-anthem-component="imageslider:12339574"></div></div>
<p id="hCksvs">But what you <em>do</em> get is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24154473/google-pixel-8a-camera-hands-on">really darn good for a budget phone</a>. The Pixel 8 Pro produced cleaner night mode photos when the aurora borealis made a rare appearance over Seattle, but overall, the 8A offers very good night and portrait modes. Plus, you get all of the helpful photo processing tricks Pixel phones have been doing for years (face unblur is a godsend for toddler photos). </p>
<p id="i3mv0A">There’s the new stuff, too, like Magic Editor and Best Take, if you <em>really</em> want to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23902248/google-photos-pixel-8-ai-magic-editor-best-take-audio-magic-eraser">mess with the time / space continuum</a> and use generative AI to mix and match expressions in your photos or replace the sky. I thought I’d use Best Take more often than I do in reality — I considered swapping my son’s facial expression with one from another photo, but I felt too weird about the results. They were just not quite right, and I’d have to live with the knowledge that it was a photo of a moment that technically never happened. Anyway, it’s there, and you can use it if you’re less queasy about that kind of thing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="Google Pixel 8A in aloe green showing back panel." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9jygPA7MLrVOfxAhFiT7pTK3_ho=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451806/DSC07460_processed.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>A budget phone with great long-term prospects.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="lilGX0">It feels like faint praise to call the Pixel 8A “good enough,” but when you’re measuring a budget phone against its much pricier peers, “good enough” is actually pretty darn good. The camera keeps up well enough even in some very tricky scenarios. The screen is smooth enough in a world of high refresh rate displays. You can certainly buy a $500 phone with a better screen or spend a bit more and get some worthwhile upgrades — especially in terms of camera hardware.</p>
<p class="c-end-para" id="OfrNpI">But the Pixel 8A really does stand alone in its combination of good enough features, price, and seven years of promised OS updates. There’s nothing essential missing, and what it lacks in flashy features, it makes up for in sheer ROI. And for someone who wants to get the most mileage out of a budget phone, it makes a lot of sense.</p>
<p id="3ErcNM"><em>Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge</em></p>
<div><div id="nxsZz7"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12092400"></div></div></div>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24162073/google-pixel-8a-review-specs-price-camera</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24162073/google-pixel-8a-review-specs-price-camera</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[This smart smoker makes barbecuing indoors a breeze]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="A black indoor smoker on a white countertop." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cY62S7adtbSbAIwV23YSoIPEGRU=/0x0:2700x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73355486/247116_GE_Indoor_Smoker_JTuohy_0013.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption><em>The GE Profile is a smart indoor smoker — designed to keep smoke inside the oven, not in your kitchen. Wi-Fi connectivity means it works the Smart HQ app for remote control, but there’s no magic sauce here to make you BBQ whizz.</em></figcaption>
    </figure>


  <p>The GE Profile Smart Indoor Smoker delivers on its promise of bringing smoking indoors, but sadly its smarts didn’t make me a better pitmaster.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="JX0ykt">My love affair with barbecue has been a slow burn. I’m from England, where BBQ means grilling burgers and steak in the garden on a gas grill. So, when I moved to South Carolina over a decade ago, I had no clue what pulled pork was or that brisket was even a thing. I learned quickly. Smoking meat is akin to religion around these parts, and I suspect many pitmasters would view the latest gadget I’ve been testing as something akin to heresy. </p>
<p id="sW2HfO">Today, barbecue is one of my favorite dishes — brisket from <a href="https://www.lewisbarbecue.com/">Lewis Barbecue</a> in Charleston is what I would request for a last meal. However, while I fancy myself as something of an accomplished home chef, I have never had much luck smoking my own meats. So, I was intrigued to test <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GE-Filtration-Precision-Connected-Countertop/dp/B0CGXY9N5F?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">the $999.95 GE Profile Smart Indoor Smoker</a>. </p>
<p id="GF3nSw">A smart indoor smoker, GE Profile’s gadget promises an easier, quicker way to get that smokey flavor; plus, it’s literally the only option if you don’t have the space or an accommodating climate for using an outdoor smoker. I do have an outdoor smoker, but it rarely gets used. It’s huge, requires a lot of prep, and I feel compelled to smoke a lot of meat to justify using it — plus, as mentioned, I’ve not been very successful making my own barbecue.</p>
<div id="aTl619"><div data-anthem-component="productcard:12335687" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'></div></div>
<p id="QjnFic">Its main tricks are being small enough to fit on your countertop (although it’s not small) and smoking food without smoking up your kitchen. Something called <a href="https://youtu.be/UkrB5l7bYKE?rel=0">Active Smoke Filtration</a> technology and an airflow system combined with tight gaskets and seals keeps the smoke in the appliance. This worked very well. No smoke escaped the oven at all during cooking, but I still got the lovely aromas. The one thing that did come out of the gadget was heat. My kitchen got very warm while using it. </p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="NsSLkx"><q>The Smart Indoor Smoker promises an easier, quicker way to get that smokey flavor</q></aside></div>
<p id="8ElyQ0">This is because it’s essentially an oven that adds smoke flavor. Unlike a true outdoor wood-pellet smoker, the Smart Indoor Smoker doesn’t cook your food with smoke. It uses a separate heating element that does most of the hard work while the smoke infuses it with flavor. This significantly cuts down on cooking time and means you use way fewer wood pellets. But I did find meats didn’t always achieve that tenderness you get from smoking alone.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tQ8hwAXIsQS538qoqq9axqeljME=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25453617/247116_GE_Indoor_Smoker_JTuohy_0005.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The smart smoker is nicely designed — looking like a fancy toaster oven set on its side. The single door has a glass front and a cavity light, so I could watch the meat smoking. </em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="rT9E7R">If you want to smoke meat indoors, though, this is a very good way to do it. Purists might scoff, but it’s more efficient than an outdoor smoker. And while I found it hard to fit into my everyday cooking routine — it still can’t cook anything in under an hour — in the two months I tested it, I used it at least twice a week, far more often than I use my outdoor smoker. It’s super simple to use and easy to clean, and its neat Keep Warm feature meant I could put a piece of meat or some sweet potatoes in the smoker in the morning, and it would be ready for dinner time.</p>
<p id="5FX3SU">Two downsides are the price — $1,000 is a lot for a single-purpose gadget — and the size. Only consider this if you have a lot of countertop space or somewhere you can store it when it’s not in use. It’s short enough to fit under my cabinets, but not with the four inches of clearance the manual recommends. My husband didn’t want it near anything that might catch fire (he’s a firefighter and was deeply suspicious of this device, but it never caused any issues). </p>
<div id="gQcebX"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12335700"></div></div>
<p id="TMxJi8">It needs to be big so it can fit the popular barbeque meats. GE Appliances says its three removable racks allow for enough space to cook three racks of baby back ribs, a brisket, a whole chicken, up to 40 wings, or a 14-pound pork butt. I did not test these capacity limits — there’s only so much meat one family can eat. But it didn’t struggle to handle anything I put in it, from a whole chicken to two racks of ribs to a sizeable brisket (halved). </p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="40sGyF"><div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"My smart kitchen: the good, the bad, and the future ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/24087703/smart-home-kitchen-appliances"},{"title":"The smart kitchen is a great idea —&amp;nbsp;and a strange reality ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/24080158/smart-kitchen-appliances-bluetooth-vergecast"}]}'></div></aside></div>
<p id="VmGuFn">The rest of the device is similarly well-designed. It has a nice big digital display that’s easy to read, with a large dial you turn and press to select temperature and smoke level, plus digital buttons for basic functions. There are six presets for brisket, pork ribs, pork butt, chicken wings, chicken breast, and salmon that can be activated from the device or GE Appliance’s Smart HQ app. Then there’s a customize option for setting your own smoke. The app isn’t required, but it offers some tips and tricks and can alert you when the door is left open, when the smoker is preheated, or when the food is almost done, which is handy.</p>
<p id="nJsojO">To start a smoke, I selected one of the presets, chose whether to use the built-in temperature probe or a set cook time (annoyingly, you can’t use both), added the pellets, filled the water bucket — where the pellets go to be extinguished — and pressed start on the machine. Once it reached the set temperature, I had to press start again (which I couldn’t do remotely), and the smoking got underway. </p>
<div id="WyV1Kt"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12335697"></div></div>
<p id="b3vUyV">The smoker did a great job infusing everything I cooked with a lovely smokey flavor, ranging from mild for shorter cook times to really rich for meats that were slow-cooked over eight to 10 hours. I liked that I could monitor and control the device from the app and use voice commands with Alexa to adjust the temperature. </p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="QUDkLc"><q>The smoker did a great job infusing everything I cooked with a lovely smokey flavor</q></aside></div>
<p id="7eC9AI">But its smarts are limited. As is common with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24087703/smart-home-kitchen-appliances">smart kitchen devices</a>, I couldn’t remotely start the appliance. I was also disappointed that the smoker couldn’t automatically adjust the cooking temperatures for me. The <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.traeger.com%2Fpellet-grills%2Fironwood%2F885&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24159117%2Fge-profile-smart-indoor-smoker-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Traeger smart smoker</a> I have will adjust the temperatures over a long smoke, which takes a lot of the guesswork out of barbecuing. The GE Profile smart smoker required frequent manual intervention for bigger meats like brisket, including rotating the meat since the compartment doesn’t heat evenly.</p>
<div id="6vp0FA">
<div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="GE Profile Smart Indoor Smoker|116641" data-volume-uuid="6d364210a" data-volume-id="116641" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-929" class="volume-video"></div>
<div class="caption"><em>The smoker keeps all the smoke inside and has a button to clear the smoke before you open the door. But in this slow-motion video, I opened the door while smoking to show the amount of smoke it generates and where it comes from inside the oven.</em></div>
</div>
<p id="lGjT8z">Sadly, my manual intervention was not successful. While all the meats I cooked had excellent smokey flavor, my two attempts at pork butt and three tries at briskets all came out chewy. Chicken, salmon, and sweet potatoes were all fine, but those more complicated meats I struggled to get right. </p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="JpZGvm"><div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"This smart mixer did not make me a better baker ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/23998244/ge-profile-smart-mixer-review"}]}'></div></aside></div>
<p id="NsIl6j">To be fair, I struggle with those in the Traeger, too, but the GE Profile smart smoker didn’t make me a better pitmaster. That’s still a skill I guess a machine can’t learn. In retrospect (and based on a <a href="https://girlscangrill.com/recipe/smoked-brisket-on-the-ge-profile-indoor-smoker/">similar experience this professional griller</a> had with the smart smoker), it’s likely that using the Keep Warm setting overcooked my meats. It takes a while for the internal temperature to get back down, so I probably needed to adjust the cook time to account for that. </p>
<p id="1ZByty">What would be great is if this smart smoker was smart enough to do that for me. Or smart enough to adjust the cooking temperature automatically during a smoke so that the meat comes out tender every time. While this innovative gadget brings something new to the kitchen, right now, its smart features are fairly basic. Smart kitchen gadgets that help you cook are great, but what I want most from the smart kitchen are smart devices that help you be a <em>better</em> cook. </p>
<p id="24iUpG"><em>Photos by Jennifer Pattison Tuohy / The Verge</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24159117/ge-profile-smart-indoor-smoker-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24159117/ge-profile-smart-indoor-smoker-review</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>