<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Republished verge Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is the scheduled republished verge RSS Feed.]]></description><link>https://zmattingly.github.io/rss-republish</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:03:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zmattingly.github.io/rss-republish/verge.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>The first headphones from Sonos deliver on comfort, sound, and more — with a unique TV Audio Swap feature that’s very convenient (when it works). But the ongoing app fiasco casts a cloud over the company’s big moment.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mTG5u1">Sonos is going through <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/22/24162168/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-new-app-design-interview">a tumultuous period</a>. Its redesigned app has gotten mixed reviews, to put it lightly, and there’s a widespread perception that Sonos released it in an undercooked state because the company was hell-bent on shipping its first-ever headphones on time. The $449 Sonos Ace headphones are hitting their June 5th launch target. Was it worth it?</p>
<p id="IFtSpk">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24160772/sonos-ace-headphones-hands-on-preview">my first look at the Ace</a>, I applauded their hardware design and premium feel. And I’ve remained impressed over the course of reviewing them. Sonos has nailed style, fit, and comfort to such an extent that I keep forgetting these are a debut product in a new category for the company. They also largely deliver on sound quality, noise cancellation, and a transparency mode that’s second only to Apple’s in how lifelike and natural it sounds.</p>
<p id="36NNTb">That’s all before you get to the signature trick of these headphones: TV Audio Swap. When it works, you can instantly transfer any sound coming from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the headphones with the press of a button. This private listening mode supports spatial audio and head tracking to ramp up the immersion when watching movies, and it works with any input device running through your TV — be it an Apple TV, Roku, or gaming console. </p>
<div><div id="PAeQnG"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12346182"></div></div></div>
<p id="UVnBsC">But true to the state of Sonos in mid-2024, the Ace headphones can be buggy. TV Audio Swap <em>doesn’t</em> always work flawlessly. And for now, this marquee feature is only available to Ace buyers who also own an $800 soundbar and an iPhone or iPad; Android compatibility won’t arrive until later this year. For everyone in the Android crowd, these are simply a nice pair of noise-canceling headphones — but they’re completely detached from the Sonos ecosystem. That leaves little incentive to choose the Ace over Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23067645/sony-wh-1000xm5-noise-canceling-headphones-review">WH-1000XM5</a> or Sennheiser’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review">Momentum 4</a> headphones until Sonos follows through on adding TV Audio Swap. And no matter what phone you have, the Ace can’t be grouped with other Sonos speakers. That means no listening to vinyl records through them; it works with any input going into your <em>TV</em>, not any input going into your Sonos system.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVKutxfhmaCLOZCJeMLo_0HE32A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475342/DSCF7284.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Ace headphones look like a hybrid of Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="bh76wC">Nailing the fundamentals on the first try</h2>
<p id="Som20M">Still, the hardware makes a great first impression. The Ace headphones come in a felt-covered case that’s made from recycled plastics. I’m always concerned about how much bag space non-folding headphones will take up, but the Ace’s case is nicely flat, which helps make it easier to take on the go. Inside is a pouch that attaches to the case magnetically: this is where you’ll store the included USB-C and USB-C-to-3.5mm cables. (Wired listening is possible with either cable.)</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rumfpHR_vpG9FEGtPVLOeacGS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475343/DSCF7289.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The carrying case includes a small pouch for cables.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="0aAsob">The Ace look like a blend of the 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max. They’re understated yet stylish. The embossed Sonos logo on the right ear cup calls little attention and is easy to miss in most lighting. The stainless steel slider arms allow for precise fit adjustments — though, as usual, my giant head requires full extension. And the magnetic memory foam ear cushions just pull right off if you ever need to replace them. The insides are different colors to help you orient the headphones, but I’ve found it easier to just remember that the metal Content Key slider always goes on the right side. I’m curious how the pleather headband will hold up over time, but in most respects, the Ace are a fantastically made set of headphones that balance sophistication and subtlety.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block"><div class="c-image-grid">
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF2EdZKsMOVc0ppIo3BS1KuwOYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475374/DSCF7374.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Sonos prototyped over 20 shades of white before deciding on this one.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<div class="c-image-grid__item">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klIQkVkBWK0FOoBtIURPZWyJlWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475377/DSCF7378.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The ear cushions are easily removable.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
</div></div>
<p id="qu4xGW">And damn, are they comfortable. The headphones are 0.69 pounds, which doesn’t match the airy feel of Bose’s QuietComfort Headphones (0.52 pounds) but is noticeably lighter than the AirPods Max (0.85 pounds), especially the longer you wear them. For my fellow glasses people, the clamping force never put too much pressure on my frames. However, the Ace lack any water resistance rating, so work out with them at your own risk. </p>
<p id="wkY9jg">The headphones have physical controls, which I favor over touchpads and swipe gestures. On the right ear cup is the Content Key, which can slide up or down to adjust volume. You press it once to play / pause, twice to skip forward a track, or three times to go back. Holding down the Content Key engages TV Audio Swap. Below the slider is a round button that toggles between active noise cancellation and the “aware” transparency mode. On the left ear cup is the USB-C port along with a power / Bluetooth pairing button. The Ace support multipoint Bluetooth, so they can be paired with two devices at the same time. They’ve also got on-head detection and automatically pause your music if you remove them. Battery life stretches to a lengthy 30 hours.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4BskmxKMlLXa_R0VQNf9ZUkTppM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475360/DSCF7406_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The Content Key is the button you’ll be using most often.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="PP4RrY">For everyday music listening, these headphones don’t introduce any groundbreaking Wi-Fi capabilities; everything happens over Bluetooth. iPhone owners get the standard AAC codec, while <em>some</em> Android phones can take advantage of Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive to wirelessly stream music at up to lossless quality. (My Galaxy S24 Ultra isn’t capable of this, so your mileage may vary.) I wish Sony’s more universal LDAC Bluetooth codec had been included for those who really care. It’s easy to get hung up on this stuff, and a headphone’s tuning is ultimately more important. But it’s fair to want all the things when you’re paying $450.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktu3dDVVOt2STtMFIlb1bS6o-UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475350/DSCF7369.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The headphones last for up to 30 hours on a charge.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="bMnMnb">As for how Sonos’ first headphones actually sound, the answer is quite nice. They’re firmly in the same ballpark as top-tier wireless headphones from brands that have been in this game for ages. The Ace favor balance and overall fidelity over boomy bass, so they’re not as in-your-face as Sony’s 1000XM5. But the expansive soundstage gives plenty of life and breadth to Billie Eilish’s <em>Hit Me Hard and Soft</em>. They’re also strong at rock, providing ample punch throughout The Black Keys’ latest album, <em>Ohio Players</em>. Beyoncé’s “16 Carriages” is another example of the Ace’s range and focus on detail, separation, crisp highs, and crystal-clear vocals. I’ll leave the frequency response charts to others, but I’ve been very pleased with the audio signature of the Ace so far. You can adjust treble and bass EQ in the Sonos app, and the headphones have the same “loudness” feature as Sonos speakers that can boost highs and lows at reduced volume levels. </p>
<div id="BEvCvV">
<div class="iframely-embed"><div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 177.7778%;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@chriswelch/post/C7wTKa5uVVs" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.threads.net%2F%40chriswelch%2Fpost%2FC7wTKa5uVVs&amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"></a></div></div>
<script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>
<p id="a8dQ9P">The company has promised “world-class” quality from Ace’s active noise cancellation and transparency modes, and it made good on at least one of those fronts — but it isn’t ANC. Don’t get me wrong: the Ace deliver noise-canceling powers that are beyond adequate. But Bose doesn’t need to worry about losing its crown. Both it and Sony still do better at silencing the outside world. Where Sonos has genuinely impressed me is with its aware mode, which pipes in your surroundings in a strikingly natural quality. It’s the closest any company besides Apple has come to that “feels like you’re not wearing headphones” sensation. This passthrough mode will make the Ace all the more useful when traveling (to hear announcements) or if you need to have a quick interaction with someone.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AB2acsKh5Re85M9Fd6otlRMjp7k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475348/DSCF7363.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>For now, TV Audio Swap can only be set up from an iOS device.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="7RGQLQ">TV Audio Swap isn’t a new concept, but Sonos does it better</h2>
<p id="W91xTH">Then we come to the headlining feature — for half the smartphone population, that is. TV Audio Swap lets you instantly transfer the sound from a Sonos Arc soundbar to the Ace headphones with a long press of the Content Key. It takes about a second, you’ll hear a short tone, and the audio from your TV starts coming through the headphones. Do the same action again, and the audio is beamed back over to the soundbar (at a safely low volume to avoid sudden loud bursts). Unlike with music playback, this home theater mode <em>does</em> form a direct Wi-Fi connection between the Ace and Arc, though the resulting audio is still a lossy 345Kbps. Sonos says both generations of its Beam and the entry-level Ray soundbar will gain support for TV Audio Swap “soon.” </p>
<p id="hsXMtJ">You can also trigger TV Audio Swap from within the Sonos app, and that’s where you’ll enable spatial audio and head tracking. Spatial audio gives you a more cinematic experience when watching content that includes a 5.1 or Atmos surround mix. Even for stereo content, Sonos will virtualize a spatial audio mix. You can always turn the feature off to hear regular stereo through the headphones. Which mode sounds the best will largely come down to what it is that you’re watching. Spatial audio worked wonders during <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em> and often makes action sequences more captivating, but I rarely felt compelled to bother for regular TV viewing.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wi_r2OWMbLPDhUY5ApqmbvFlw-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475383/DSCF7355.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>TV Audio Swap lets you privately listen to your TV (or anything plugged into it).</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="nswK6R">The headphones can play any audio that would normally come through your soundbar — and that includes games. The latency is impressively low: it was imperceptible to me when playing a few games of <em>MLB The Show </em>on PS5, where the crack of the bat seemed right on target. I’m not a shooter guy, but the gunplay audio in <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart,</em> and <em>GTA V</em> kept up with what I was seeing on-screen. Competitive gamers might feel differently, but for casual pass-the-time gaming, the Ace are more than up for the job.</p>
<p id="7rUotQ">Right now, I can take or leave the dynamic head tracking. That might change when Sonos adds another upcoming feature, TrueCinema, which will calibrate the surround effect based on your specific viewing environment to trick your brain into thinking there’s really an array of speakers around you. But like so much about TV Audio Swap — Android support, wider soundbar compatibility, etc. — TrueCinema is also in the “coming later” column.</p>
<p id="Qezkno">When TV Audio Swap works as advertised, it’s super impressive and helps differentiate the Ace headphones in a big way. I can come home, turn on my TV, hold down the Content Key, and privately listen to a wide range of entertainment sources. You can pair AirPods with an Apple TV box, sure, but you <em>can’t</em> use Apple’s earbuds as the default audio source for everything plugged into your TV; only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23578606/apple-homepod-2-second-gen-2023-siri-smart-speaker-review">HomePods</a> can do that. The versatility of TV Audio Swap is a huge selling point and what sets the Sonos Ace headphones apart.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt="A photo of the Sonos Ace wireless headphones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b670mBJ80mjweZQhvMM5IyTJp24=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25475356/DSCF7381_Enhanced_NR.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>The exterior plastic has a coating to help reduce fingerprints and smudges.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="TowsGH">Unfortunately, it has proven inconsistent for me. A few times when holding down the Content Key, I’ve heard a “thunk” sound and nothing happens. When this occurs, tapping the TV Audio Swap button in the app also does nothing — despite the headphones showing as connected. Turning them off and on again is usually enough to get the feature working smoothly again. In general, I’ve had more luck activating TV Audio Swap with the Content Key instead of the app. Should I chalk this up to the new Sonos app’s general bugginess? Probably, but it’s worth mentioning and something I’ll keep an eye on. Sonos spokesperson Julia Fasano described it as “a rare bug that our team is currently aware of and working to address in a future release.”</p>
<h2 id="sCyRN7">The Ace (and app) needed just a little more time</h2>
<p id="Z32T11">The Sonos Ace will arrive to early customers as a pair of noise-canceling headphones that belong in the same conversation as the best from Apple, Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony. For a first effort, the company got more right than wrong and nailed the fundamentals. The Ace are wonderfully comfortable, they sound good, and they hold their own in regard to ANC. </p>
<p id="czkWyP">But the undeniable truth is that these headphones feel rushed. Sonos clearly had a release timeframe in mind that it was unwilling to budge on. With consumer demand for soundbars and speakers continuing to shrink, this is a company in need of diversifying its business — and doing it fast. But the Ace headphones desperately could’ve used some extra months of polish before this launch. As is, Android phone owners can’t enjoy their most unique feature, and <em>everyone</em> will need Sonos’ priciest soundbar to experience TV Audio Swap until an unspecified time in the future. </p>
<div><div id="svAMLz"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12347477"></div></div></div>
<p class="c-end-para" id="QSfJZ9">Sonos CEO Patrick Spence told me headphones are its most requested product ever, which likely contributed to this hurried release. But I wish the company had shown more patience. An alternate universe where the Ace arrived a few months later — with all features ready for everyone out of the gate — would have made them land with greater impact. It also would’ve given Sonos precious time to further refine the new app, sparing both the company and its customers major headaches and an avalanche of frustration across social media and Reddit. Sonos seems confident that the gamble will still pay off. We’ll all find out soon enough.</p>
<p id="YY9WUb"><em>Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge</em></p>
<p id="ckGWhI"><em><strong>Correction, June 3rd:</strong></em><em> This review originally stated that multiple Ace headphones can be used with a single Arc soundbar. At the Ace preview event last month, Sonos told media that this would be possible — but the company has since clarified that only one pair of headphones can be used at a time.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bluetti SwapSolar review: power and chill with swappable batteries]]></title><description><![CDATA[
  <p>Sharing this solar generator’s batteries with a 3-in-1 solar fridge, freezer, and ice-making combo is a good idea that might get better.</p> <p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="UK8dnL">Solar generators and battery-powered fridges are highly desirable additions to vans, boats, cabins, and sheds, or anywhere power and refrigeration is needed off the grid. Both are meant to be portable by necessity but suffer from the same issue: weight. </p>
<p id="bpxFI6">Bluetti just started shipping its <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bluettipower.com%2Fpages%2Fac180t&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">SwapSolar kit</a> that pairs an AC180T solar generator with its MultiCooler, a 3-in-1 solar-powered fridge, freezer, and ice maker. What makes this kit interesting is that the MultiCooler and AC180T devices can share the same B70 LFP batteries, which can be charged inside either device when plugged into your car’s 12V socket, a standard power outlet, or solar panels. </p>
<p id="src0dI">This modular approach has some other interesting benefits, too:</p>
<ul>
<li id="tLSJjz">Divide these heavy devices into multiple components for easier transport.</li>
<li id="fQL8bL">Worry less about charging batteries or buying bigger ones by getting as many B70 batteries as you need to cover your average roadtrip, workday, or home blackout.</li>
<li id="DN6Lhn">Repair or replace just the battery or the unit it powers should something go wrong or upgrades become available.</li>
</ul>
<p id="MzmJif">Building a modular ecosystem of products around small interchangeable batteries has already seen success by makers of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/3/20/17141972/makita-cm501dz-rugged-coffee-maker-cordless">handheld power tools</a>. Bluetti is expanding the concept to devices needed for extended off-grid living, with more SwapSolar products coming. </p>
<p id="C4Q9Fb">Great, but first we need to see if the devices shipping today can independently justify the total price of the $2,000 SwapSolar kit. </p>
<p id="e6K6SX"><em><strong>Editor’s note: </strong></em><em>When this review was finished, we went back to take one last photo and discovered that the MultiCooler would not turn on for reasons explained below. We are therefore withholding its score until Bluetti can assure us it’s not a widespread defect.</em></p>
<div>
<div id="7P4JvO"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12324084"></div></div>
<div id="7tymy5"><div data-anthem-component="scorecard:12324085"></div></div>
</div>
<p id="iuLYGm">The SwapSolar B70 battery at the heart of these systems holds 716.8Wh of energy and is built using LFP chemistry. LFP — short for lithium iron phosphate — batteries last longer, are safer, and work in a wider range of operating temperatures than the smaller and lighter NMC-based batteries they’re rapidly replacing. The B70 should hold 80 percent of its original charging capacity, even after 3,000 cycles.</p>
<p id="B5ZqtP">Bluetti will sell you as many B70 batteries as you’d like, but right now, they only work with the AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler. The AC180T can be powered by one or two batteries, while the MultiCooler fits only one.</p>
  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Irce7ULMeUZJ1BlFzRCIgpYTY6w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25466129/Hover_20240426_1714137151896.0_ezgif.com_optimize_ezgif.com_optimize.gif">
      <figcaption><em>The AC180T solar generator fitted with two hot-swappable B70 batteries will continue charging my laptop uninterrupted after one battery is removed to power the MultiCooler.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<h2 id="HVlSBk">MultiCooler </h2>
<p id="zjtMLD">The 3-in-1 MultiCooler (model F045D) refrigerator, freezer, and ice maker is very similar to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23987611/ecoflow-glacier-review-ice-maker-refrigerator-freezer-vanlife-boatlife-specs-price">EcoFlow Glacier I reviewed</a> last year. However, the MultiCooler lacks EcoFlow’s dual-zone feature that lets you divide the main compartment into both a freezer and fridge that can run <em>simultaneously</em>. That could be a deal-breaker for some. On the other hand, Bluetti’s MultiCooler runs longer on battery and is usually a little quieter.</p>
<p id="TGqHkR">Noise is a critical factor for any device that runs all night within earshot of your bed in an RV, cabin, or boat. Bluetti’s MultiCooler is thankfully nearly silent until the compressor kicks in. Then it gets about as loud as a home theater projector, or about 35dB in my testing, as it cools the unit down. Cooling is relatively slow, however. Even with the refrigeration mode set to Max in the Bluetti app, it took 23 minutes to go from room temperature to 6 degrees Celsius / 43 degrees Fahrenheit and then another 17 minutes to reach -10C / 14F. That’s slower, but quieter, than the EcoFlow Glacier.</p>
<div id="5teQHe"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12325428"></div></div>
<p id="eMaG7Q">Bluetti consistently reported a lower temperature than my own trusty thermometer during testing. For example, my thermometer placed inside the unit read -8C / 17.6F when the app and MultiCooler display read -10C / 14F, and when the MultiCooler said it was 3C / 37.4F, the thermometer read 5C / 41F. At least it was consistently inconsistent, which is something I can work around.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vBKxMxCAO6gKeAQ5ErSfAnsQ0HI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25431529/IMG_4066.jpg">
      <figcaption><em>Smart plug visualization showing the MultiCooler operating as a refrigerator before 11AM and freezer after. Each power spike corresponds to the compressor coming on to cool the device. It used 308Wh from the wall jack on this particular day.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p id="jxZxQX">The unit goes almost completely silent once it hits your defined temperature set in the app or on the physical display, interrupted by a few bubbles and scratches now and again that likely won’t be too annoying for most people. The compressor runs for about 10 minutes at around 33dB, followed by 20- to 40-minute gaps of near silence in my testing. It turns on with what sounds like five distinct clicks of a mechanical button and turns off with a slight rattle that’s noticeable when empty (the lightweight food baskets inside the fridge shake).</p>
<p id="TaGfC1">Ice making is a much noisier affair, as you’d expect, and occurs in its own dedicated compartment — not in the freezer. The first batch of ice takes about 23 minutes as the MultiCooler produces a loud 48dB from a distance of one meter. The noise is constant and only stops about one minute before the ice drops into the bucket. Each batch thereafter is just as loud but only takes about 12 minutes. You can select between small or large ice, which yields a sheet of two dozen small (or less small) hollow cubes. It can produce ice continuously until the one-liter water reservoir is empty — that’s about 100 cubes. In my testing, the ice was about half melted after being left in the closed bucket for six hours.</p>
<p id="L4uhZV">One quirk of making ice is that Bluetti stops cooling the main compartment to do it. That should be fine in all but the hottest environments, so long as the lid is left closed. To test the quality of the insulation, I turned off the MultiCooler that had been operating for a day at -10C / 14F while half full of frozen food. According to the app, it measured -8C / 17.6F after one hour, -6C / 21.2 F after two hours, and -5C / 23F after three hours. It was still at 1C / 34F some 14 hours later.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><div id="02mIGp"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12321371"></div></div></div>
<p id="COVGRq">Battery life is very good. In Max refrigeration mode, I was able to bring the temperature down to -10C / 14F, make four batches of ice, and then maintain that temperature for 36 hours before a recharge was needed. In Eco mode, I started the timer when the temperature was already -10C / 14F, made two batches of ice, and maintained the temperature for 40 hours before the battery died. In both cases, the battery quit inelegantly with an E1 error (low battery voltage protection) at about 5 percent charge left. Bluetti tells me “this is normal” which is... come on.</p>
<p id="WF5D6r">Bluetti provides adapters to power the MultiCooler by three other methods: a 12V / 24V DC connection to a car socket; a standard AC wall jack; or up to 200W of direct connected solar panels, but only if there’s a battery inside. Bluetti didn’t provide any charging data like watts, voltage, and current when I connected a 200W solar panel to the MultiCooler — it just shows it charging on the display and in the app. The unit can make ice no matter how the unit is powered, unlike the EcoFlow Glacier.</p>
<p id="LuH6wU">The MultiCooler includes a handle and wheels as standard, which make it relatively easy to transport over flat ground when fully loaded. It’s still heavy even without the B70 battery installed, and the wheels are rather small, resulting in limited ground clearance — that means occasionally having to drag the MultiCooler over rougher terrains.</p>
<p id="uUzdW2">Unfortunately, as I was wrapping up this review, I found that the MultiCooler would not turn on after sitting idle for about a week. It is now back with Bluetti, and a preliminary report suggests that my issue was caused by a heatsink detaching from a MOS tube — a critical voltage control element on the MultiCooler’s circuitry — possibly as a result of rough handling during shipment. Bluetti will now determine if this is a one-off situation or a general defect that requires changes in the manufacturing and assembly process. </p>
<p id="1GF5dg">We will update this review and add a MultiCooler score when we get the final analysis from Bluetti.</p>
<p id="9VIyxc">I should also note that while 3-in-1 fridge, freezer, and ice-making combos are impressive in all they can do, they are also expensive compared to simple 12V portable car fridges that cost less than half as much. But those won’t make ice from the power of the Saharan sun, so what’s even the point?</p>
<h2 id="ak8Iv9">AC180T </h2>
<p id="niGiVE">The AC180T solar generator is a nicely designed power station with a built-in MPPT charge controller to connect solar panels. Nearly all the outputs and display can be conveniently found on the front, with the AC input on the side. A lid on the top hides the two B70 slots, which are keyed to ensure the batteries are inserted correctly, for a total capacity of 1.43kWh.</p>
<p id="TEp5zg">For context, 1.43kWh is enough to keep a 6000BTU window air conditioner (400W) running for about six hours, boil about 35 liters of water from a 1000W electric kettle, or keep a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23181342/starlink-rv-review-trees-rain-speed-latency">Starlink internet from space system</a> running for about a day and a half.</p>
<p id="BseOvA">Bluetti’s modular approach really helps to divvy up the weight of the AC180T. Each 5.3 × 6.3 × 13.8in / 134 × 160 × 350mm battery weighs 18.7lbs / 8.5kg, which brings the total weight of the AC180T up to 58.4lbs / 26.5kg when both are inserted — that’s a lot for most people to carry.</p>
<div id="FFg1CF"><div data-anthem-component="gallery:12325433"></div></div>
<p id="DGCmUv">When plugged into an AC wall jack and in the fastest “Turbo” mode, charging two batteries from zero to 100 percent took 77 minutes and produced about 44dB of noise (from one meter away) while drawing 1.4kW from the grid. Charging in Standard mode still produced 44dB but pulled only 920W, while Silent mode dropped things down to 37dB and 735W. Charging a single battery in Turbo mode took 66 minutes and pulled a steady 860W. In all cases, charging began to slow down at around 95 percent full, as you’d expect.</p>
<p id="Zw6ov4">I also tested Bluetti’s claim that the AC180T can produce up to 1200W of continuous AC output with one battery inserted or up to 1800W with two hot-swappable batteries.</p>
<p id="iEf7xo">With one battery installed, I was able to run a microwave at around 1250W for three minutes without issue, but a 2100W hair dryer resulted in an inverter overload, causing it to shut down for safety. I then added the second battery and plugged in the same hair dryer, which ran fine at a steady 1874W, until I plugged in a 1200W toaster for a total load of 3074W, which quickly shut down the inverter with another overload. No smells, no funny noises, no mess, as you’d hope. So, both tests passed.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><div id="rFQhJA"><div data-anthem-component="aside:12321372"></div></div></div>
<p id="YyhZzj">To test the hot-swappable claim, I started the 1250W microwave with two batteries inserted. It continued to run as I removed and reinserted one of the batteries. I then unplugged the microwave and plugged in the hair dryer, drawing 900W, which continued to blow as I removed and reinserted a battery. I then bumped the heat to max (drawing over 1850W) with two batteries installed, pulled one, and the hair dryer shut off within seconds. Good.</p>
<p id="pb4yqo">As with all power stations, the AC inverter will drain the battery when left on. With no load attached and the AC output turned on, my two AC180T batteries (1.43kWh) dropped 30 percent in 24 hours. That works out to about 17.92Wh lost per hour, or a steady 18W just to power the inverter, which is fairly efficient. Still, you should enable Bluetti’s AC Eco mode (on by default) to automatically turn off the AC inverter after a user-defined time of low or no load. Otherwise, those fully charged batteries will die in just over three days.</p>
<p id="4WEInu">For what it’s worth, I was able to plug the MultiCooler directly into the 12V / 10A DC car jack on the AC180T with the included cable, which obviates the need to swap batteries if you can keep the units close together. You can also power the fridge off the AC180T’s AC port, of course, but DC is more efficient (no wasteful inverter). </p>
<p id="mdDuT3">The Bluetti app is fine, but it’s cluttered with promotions and only works with the MultiCooler and AC180T over Bluetooth, not Wi-Fi like EcoFlow’s products. That means you’ll have to be nearby to check on your battery status or to adjust temperatures.</p>
<div class="c-wide-block">  <figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K6WKfc4WOcwkto39qvpDPfzmYaw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25434067/Hover_20240425_1714135816951.0.jpeg">
      <figcaption><em>Me writing this review from a remote workplace flanked by a Bluetti AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler to keep my Negroni on ice.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<h2 id="ADSDKf">Conclusion</h2>
<p id="GMpSwd">On their own, the SwapSolar AC180T solar generator and MultiCooler 3-in-1 fridge are each very competitive products — assuming, of course, that the defect on my MultiCooler review unit was an isolated issue. If so, then Bluetti’s SwapSolar kit is a winning combination.</p>
<p id="3AM8J4">Regardless, I hope to see Bluetti’s modular ecosystem approach adopted by competitors like EcoFlow, Jackery, and others. A company called <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.runhoodpower.com%2Fproducts%2Frallye-1200-pro-1296wh-1200w-portable-power-station-with-100w-solar-panel%3Fvariant%3D47815111639354&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Runhood</a> has already been selling less powerful <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.runhoodpower.com%2Fproducts%2Frallye-1200-pro-1296wh-1200w-portable-power-station-with-100w-solar-panel&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">solar generators with modular batteries</a> and accessories for over a year.</p>
<p id="3ewdOG">What SwapSolar is missing, however, is a small portable charging accessory to independently charge each B70 battery. Bluetti’s Evelyn Zou tells me that a “base” is in development to do exactly that. Then you only need to bring the base and battery into a shop, cafe, or gym to get things charged, instead of conspicuously dragging in the entire fridge or solar generator. The base will also convert the B70 battery into a standalone power source for your USB gadgets. Zou says that Bluetti is looking to expand the SwapSolar ecosystem in the future and is “actively working on new products.” But those are just promises for now, with no dates or prices. </p>
<p id="4arhCZ">Ideally, owners of the AC180T and MultiCooler and any other SwapSolar device could even upgrade to compatible batteries with improved chemistry over time. Or maybe it opens up a market to cheaper third-party alternatives. We’ll see!</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="4FBWpQ"><q>For the MultiCooler, my advice is to wait or look elsewhere until Bluetti explains itself</q></aside></div>
<p id="8RaKOZ">Bluetti is selling the <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bluettipower.com%2Fproducts%2Fac180t&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AC180T directly for $1,099</a>. But the MultiCooler is still in that weird <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%23%2F&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Indiegogo “indemand” phase</a> — which means you’ll have to wait until August, according to Bluetti, if you prefer to buy directly from the company and avoid all the Indiegogo “perk” nonsense. The AC180T is covered by a five-year warranty, which drops to two years for the MultiCooler.</p>
<p id="77CRjS">For the MultiCooler, my advice is to wait or look elsewhere until Bluetti explains itself. </p>
<p id="0pa0N7">The SwapSolar MultiCooler and AC180T combo kit is currently priced at <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$1,999</a> on Indiegogo. That sounds about right given that a comparable system from EcoFlow that combines the Glacier 3-in-1 fridge with a less powerful River 2 Pro solar generator currently sells for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fglacier-portable-refrigerator-river-2-pro-portable-power-station-1%3Fvariant%3D40540240478281&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$1,499</a> or <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.ecoflow.com%2Fproducts%2Fglacier-portable-refrigerator-delta-2-max-portable-power-station%3Fvariant%3D40543489818697&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$2,799 when paired with a more powerful Delta 2 Max</a>. The AC180T lists for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$999</a> while the MultiCooler can be purchased separately for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fbluetti-swapsolar-an-ecosystem-multicooler%2Fpayments%2Fnew%23%2Freview&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F24145138%2Fmulticooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$799</a> (without a B70 battery).</p>
<p id="7k3bSw"><em>Photography by Thomas Ricker / The Verge</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24145138/multicooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24145138/multicooler-ac180t-modular-battery-review-price-specs</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 06:18:18 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>